THE 
Amorous Prince, 
OR, THE 
Curious Husband. 
A 
COMEDY, 
As it is Acted at his Royal Highness, the 
Duke of Yorl(s Theatre. 
Written by’ M“ A. BE H N. 
Sgi SI S vf5 
tie sis 
LONDON , 
Printed by J. M. for Thomas Dring, at the White Lyon next 
Chancery-Lane-End in Fleet-ftreeU 1671 .
PROLOGUE 
tf X 
c\ 
W Ell! you expert a Prologue to the Play, 
And you expect it too Petition-way 5 
With Chapeau bas 3 bejeeching you t'excuft, 
A damn'd Intrigue of an unpractic'd Mufe 5 
Tell you it's fortune waits upon your fniles, 
And when you frown, Lord how you kill the whiles ! 
Or elfe to rally up the (ins of th' Age, 
And bring each Fop in Town upon the Stage 
And in one Prologue run more vices ore, 
Then either Court or City knew before'-) 
And that's a wonder which ivill pleaje you too, 
But my Commijjion s not to pleaje you now. 
Firft then for you grave Dons who love no play 
But what is regular , Great Johnfon’ sway'-, 
Who hate the Monlieur with the Farce and Dr oil, 
But arc for things well faidwith fpirit and foul', 
'Tisyou I mean whofe judgments will admits 
No Interludes of fooling with your Wit 5 
Tou re here defeated, and anon will cry 
s'Death ! wou'd 'twere treafonto write Comedy. 
So ! there's a party loft 5 now for the reft, 
Who fwear they drather hear a fmutty jeft 
Spoken by Nokes?r Angel ? then aScene ' 
Of the admir'd and well-pennd Cataline} 
Who love the Comtek. Hat, the jig and Dance, 
Things that are fitted to their Ignorance : 
Tou too are quite undone, for here's no Farce, 
Damn me!you lcry, this Play will be mine A - i - 
Not ferious, nor yet Comtek, what is't the?z$ 
Th' imperfett iftue of a Lukewarm brain : 
9 Twas born before it's time, and fuch a whelp. 
As all the after-lickings could not help. 
Bait it then as ye pleaje, we'le not defend it, 
But he that dif-approves it, let him mend it. 
\ 
/ Actors 
Actors Names- 
Frederick 
Son to the Duke. 
Curtins 
His Friend. 
Lorenzo Ji 
A rich extravagant Lord 3 a kind of Favourite to 
Frederick. 
Antonio 
A Nobleman of Florence. 
Alberto 
His dear Friend 3 a Noble man alfo. 
Pietro 
Man to Curtins . 
Galliard 
Servant to the Prince.  
Valet 
» 
To Antonio. 
Clarina 
Wife to Antonio. 
Ifrnena 
Sifter to Antonio 3 in love with Alberto . 
Laura 
Sifter to Lorenzo 3 in love with Curtins. 
Cloris  
Sifter to Curtius, dilguis’d like a Country Maid, 
in love with Frederick. 
Isabella 
Woman to Clarina . 
Lucia 
Maid to Cloris . 
Guilliam . 
Man to cloris, a Country-fellow. 
Page/  Mufckc 
Scene the Court of Florence. 
\ v 
,. 
PRO- 
A U 
; % A 
VIA A V 
\ , -A 
v 
»v 
t 
THE
	<l>ACT I. SCENE. I.</l>
	<l>The Chamber of Clotis</l>
	<l>Enter Cloris dreji in her night Mthe 0 with Frederick</l>
	<l>E>rejfing himfilfi</l>
	<l> ' _ t I ‘ .... , ., , .     .'. . >   </l>
	<l>- Clo A N D will you leave me now to fears,</l>
	<l>AA Which love it felf can hardly (atisfie ?</l>
	<l>-A. B u t thofe, and that together fure will kill me.</l>
	<l>If you (lay long away.</l>
	<l>Fred . My Dear, ’tis almoft day, and we mud: part $</l>
	<l>Should thofe rude eyes, ’mongft whom thou</l>
	<l>Dwell’ft, perceive us 5</l>
	<l>Twould prove unhappy both to thee and me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>dor .</speaker>
	<l> And will you. Sir, be conftant to your Vows ?</l>
	<l>Fred . Ah Clork ! do not queftion what I’ve fworn 5</l>
	<l>If thou would’ft have it once again repeated.</l>
	<l>Tie do’t. By all that’s good, Tie marry thee ,  -V</l>
	<l>By that moft Holy Altar, before which we kneel’d, </l>
	<l>When firft I (aw the brighteft Saint that e’re ador’d it 5 i</l>
	<l>I’le marry none but thee, my deareft Cloris . J </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, you have faid enough to gain a credit</l>
	<l>With any Maid 5 though (he had been deceiv’d</l>
	<l>Byfomefuch flatteries, as thefe before.</l>
	<l>I never knew the pains of fear till now 5 £ sighs.</l>
	<l>And you muft needs forgive the faults you make 5</l>
	<l>A  B For</l>
	<l>(<>)</l>
	<l>For had I ftill remain’d in Innocence,</l>
	<l>I (hould have ftill believ’d you.</l>
	<l>Fred . Why doft thou not hiy Love ></l>
	<l>Clor . Some doubts Ihave, but when I look on you.</l>
	<l>Though I muft olufti tofdo fo, they all yanifji > r</l>
	<l>But I provide againft your abfence. Sir. '  / </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Make noprovilion Clor is , but ofhope.</l>
	<l>Prepare thy felf againft a Wedding day,</l>
	<l>When thou (halt be a little Deity on Earth.</l>
	<l>Clor . I know not what it is to dwell in Courts,</l>
	<l>But fure it muft be fine, fince you are there 5</l>
	<l>Yet I could wifh you were an humble Shepherd,</l>
	<l>And knew no other Pallace then this Cottage 5. 1</l>
	<l>Where I would weave you Crowns, of Pinks and Dazies, .</l>
	<l>Andyoufhould be a Monarch every May. ) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> And Cloris 3 1 could be content to fit</l>
	<l>With thee, upon fome (hady Rivers bank.</l>
	<l>To hear thee Sing, and tell a Tale of Love.</l>
	<l>Forthee, Alas! I could do any thing 3</l>
	<l>A Sheep-hook I could prize above a Sword 5</l>
	<l>An Army f would quit to lead a Flock,</l>
	<l>And more efteem that Chaplet wreath’d by thee.</l>
	<l>Then the Victorious Bays:</l>
	<l>All this I could, but Dear, I have a Father,</l>
	<l>Whorn for thy fake, to make thee greaS: and glorious,</l>
	<l>I would not lofe my int’reft with.</l>
	<l>But Cloris fee, the unkind day approaches</l>
	<l>And we muft kiss and part. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Unkind it is indeed, may it prove lb.</l>
	<l>To all that with its prefence, .</l>
	<l>And pass as foon away.</l>
	<l>That welcome night, may re-aftume its place</l>
	<l>. And bring you quickly back. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> With great impatience I’le expeft that hour,  . V</l>
	<l>That fhall condudt me inits (hades to thee 3</l>
	<l>Farewel. . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>clor.</speaker>
	<l> Farewel Sir, if you muft be gone. [jBight</l>
	<l>Fred One Kiss, and then indeed jl will be gone. . RiC ijfes her.</l>
	<l>. ' '' ' .] A</l>
	<l>( 3 )</l>
	<l>Anew blown Rofe kift by the morning dew.</l>
	<l>Has not more Natural fweetness.</l>
	<l>Ah Claris I can you doubt that heart.</l>
	<l>To whom fuch bleffings you impart ?</l>
	<l>Unjuftly you fufpeift that prize.</l>
	<l>Won by fuch touches, and fuch eyes.</l>
	<l>My Faired, turn that Face away,</l>
	<l>Unless I could for ever ftay }</l>
	<l>Turn but but a little while I go. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, I muft fee thethe laft of you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> 1 dare not difobey $ adieu till evening. [Exit, Fred</l>
	<l>Enter Lucia. [</l>
	<l>Clor . How no w Lucia i is my Father up?</l>
	<l>Luc, No, not a Moufe fcirs yet} I have kept a true</l>
	<l>Watch all this night, for I was cruelly afraid</l>
	<l>Left we fhould have been furpriz’d-—</l>
	<l>Is the Prince gone ? but why do I ask.</l>
	<l>That may read it in your fad looks.</l>
	<l>Clor . Yes, he is gone, and with him too has taken. [ Sighs </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc .</speaker>
	<l> What has he taken ? riefwearyou frighten me.</l>
	<l>Clor . My heart Lucia. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> Your Heart, I am glad ’tisnoworfe. - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Why, what doft think he fhould have taken ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> A thing more hard to have been</l>
	<l>Recovered again. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> What thing prethee? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> Your Maiden-head.</l>
	<l>Clor . What’s that? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> A thing young Gallants long extremely for,</l>
	<l>And when they have it too, they (ay</l>
	<l>They care not a Dazy for the giver. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> How comeft thou fo wife Lucia .? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> Oh the fine Gentleman that comes a nights</l>
	<l>With the Prince, told me fo much, and bid me</l>
	<l>Be fure never to part with it for fine words.</l>
	<l>For men would lie as often as they fwore j</l>
	<l>And fo he bad me tell you too.</l>
	<l>Clor 0 Oh Lucia !</l>
	<l>B 2 </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>C 4 ) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> Why do you figh?, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>clo.</speaker>
	<l> Tothitik if Princes were like common Men, r</l>
	<l>How I fhould be undone.</l>
	<l>Since! have given him a!l I had'togive 3</l>
	<l>And who that looks on him can blame my faith. . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> Indeed he furpafies Dawson far $</l>
	<l>But Pde forgot my felf, you are the Princes Wife $ ' '</l>
	<l>Hefaidyou fhould be kneel’d too, and ador’d,</l>
	<l>And never look’d on but on Holy days:</l>
	<l>That many Maids fhould wait upon your call,</l>
	<l>And ftrow fine flowers for you to tread upon 5</l>
	<l>Mufickand Love fhould daily fill your ears.</l>
	<l>And all your other fenfes (hould-be ravifht -.</l>
	<l>With wonders of each kind, great as your beauty.</l>
	<l>Clor . Lucia z methinks you have learnt to fpeak fine things;  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> I have a thoufand more I’ve heard him fay 5</l>
	<l>Oh, I could liften a whole night to hear him talk:</l>
	<l>But hark, I hear a noife, the houfe is up,.. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>And.</speaker>
	<l>muft not find us here.'</l>
	<l>Clor . Lock up this Box of Jewels for me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Luc.</speaker>
	<l> Oh rare! what did thefe come tonight X- </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>dor .</speaker>
	<l> Yes, yes, away. .Exeunt.</l>
	<l>s    - ' ; 1</l>
	<l>S CE ; N E IT. A Grover \</l>
	<l>Enter. Curtins and Pietro.- </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>r </l>
	<l>.</speaker>
	<l>T .--a .  .vsk</l>
	<l>' »  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur .</speaker>
	<l> I wonder the Prince ftays fo long3 </l>
	<l>i do not like thefe night-works 3</l>
	<l>Were I not confident of Claris vertue, c ' .</l>
	<l>—Which (hall no more be tempted.</l>
	<l>Ihear feme coming, and hope tis he—   - '/'>] :v  '</l>
	<l>Pietro, are the Horfes ready?  :-:d nO .ml </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> Yes my Lord. „ \_ExitiVietro/</l>
	<l>Enter Frederick. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur..</speaker>
	<l> Sir, you are welcome from Cloris Arms. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> With much ado, I am got loofe from thole fait</l>
	<l>Fetter but not from thofc of her beauty 3</l>
	<l>By</l>
	<l>(5) '</l>
	<l>By thefe fhe (till inflames me, '</l>
	<l>Infpight of all my humours of inconftancy 3</l>
	<l>So fofeand young, fo fair and innocent.</l>
	<l>So full of Air, and yet of languifhment 5</l>
	<l>So much of Nature inher heart and eyes.</l>
	<l>So timerous and fo kind without difguife :</l>
	<l>Such untaughtTweets in every part do move,</l>
	<l>As’gainft my reafon doescompel my love.</l>
	<l>Such artless fmiles look fo unorder’d too,</l>
	<l>Gains more then all the charms of Courts can do.</l>
	<l>From head to foot a fpotless Statue feems.</l>
	<l>As Art, not Nature, had compos’d her limbs3</l>
	<l>So white, and fo unblemifht, oh Curt jus !</l>
	<l>I’meravilht beyond fenfe when I but think on’t 3</l>
	<l>How muchmore muftmy furprifebe,</l>
	<l>When I behold thefe wonders.  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> And have you feenher,Sir, in all this beauty ></l>
	<l>Oh Hell! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Curtins , I will not hide my Soul from thee 3</l>
	<l>I havefeenall the marvels ofthat Maid. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Car.</speaker>
	<l> My Soul learn nowtheArt of being difguis’d :</l>
	<l>—-’Tis much my. Lord, that one</l>
	<l>Bred in fuch Ample innocence, . . . </l>
	<l>Should learn fo foon fo much of confidence:</l>
	<l>Pray, Sir, what Arts and cunning do you ufe ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Faith time and importunity refufe no body. ' </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Is that the way ? had you no other aids ?</l>
	<l>Made younopromifetoher. Sir, of Marriage ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Oh, yes in abundance, that’s your only bait.</l>
	<l>And though they cannot hope we will perform it.</l>
	<l>Yet it fecures their Honour and my Pleafure. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Then, Sir, you have enjoy’d her } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Oh yes, and gather’d fweets -j</l>
	<l>Would make an Anchoret negleft his vow, [</l>
	<l>And think he had miftook his way to future bliss, ,</l>
	<l>Which only can be found in fuchembraces 3 \</l>
	<l>Twas hard to gain, but, Curtins when once Vidtor, j</l>
	<l>Oh how the joys of conqueft did enflave me !’</l>
	<l>CO </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> But, Sir 3 methinks ’tis much that (he (hould yields</l>
	<l>With only a barepromife that you'd marry her.</l>
	<l>Fred . Yes 3 there was fomething more— but— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> But, what Sir 3 you are not Married. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Faith yes 3 I’ve made a Vow,</l>
	<l>And that you know would go as far with any otherman. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> But (he it feems forgot you were the Prince > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> No 3 fhe urged that too,</l>
	<l>And left no arguments unus’d</l>
	<l>Might make me fenfible of what I did 3</l>
	<l>But I was fixt 3 and overcame them all 3</l>
	<l>Repeating (till my vows and paflions for her 3</l>
	<l>Till in the prefence of her Maid and Heaven</l>
	<l>Wefolemnlycontracted.</l>
	<l>N Cur. But 3 Sir 3 by your permiffion was it well > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> What would!! thou have him do</l>
	<l>That’s all on fire, and dies for an enjoyment ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> But having gain’d it 3 do you love her (till ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, yet extremely.,</l>
	<l>And would beconftantto the vows I’ve made.</l>
	<l>Were I a man, as thou art of thy felf3</l>
	<l>But with the aids of Counfels I muft chufe,</l>
	<l>And what my Soul adores I muft refufe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> This pa(Iion 3 Sir 3 pofleflion will deftroy.</l>
	<l>And you’l loveless, the more you do enjoy. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> That’s all my hope of cure 5 I’le ply that game 3</l>
	<l>And flacken by degrees th unworthy flame. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Methinks, my Lord 3 it had more generous been</l>
	<l>To’ve check’d that flame when firft it did begin.</l>
	<l>E’re you the flighted victory had won.</l>
	<l>And a poor harmless Virgin quite undone 5</l>
	<l>And what isworfe 3 you’ve made her love you too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> F aith that’s the greater mifchief of the two 3</l>
	<l>I know to fitch nice Vertuous Souls as' thine.</l>
	<l>My jufter inclination is a crime 3</l>
	<l>. Bin 1 love pleafures which thou can’ft not prize,</l>
	<l>Beyc id dull gazing on thy Miftress eyes.</l>
	<l>The lovely objedl which enflaves my heart,</l>
	<l>( 7’)</l>
	<l>Mall: yet more certain Cures then fniiles impart,</l>
	<l>—And you on Laura have the fame defign. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur .</speaker>
	<l> Yes, Sir w,hen juftify’d by Laws Divine.</l>
	<l>Fred . Divine, a pleafant warrant for your fin..</l>
	<l>Which being not made, we ne’re had guilty been 5</l>
	<l>But now we (peak of Laura,</l>
	<l>Prethee when is’t that I (hall fee that Beauty ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Never I hope [ \Afide ] I know not. Sir,</l>
	<l>Her Father (till is Cruel, and denys me,</l>
	<l>What (he and I have long made fute in vain for }</l>
	<l>But, Sir, your Intereft might prevail with him.</l>
	<l>When he (hall know I’me one whom you efteem,</l>
	<l>He will allow my flame, and my address,</l>
	<l>He whom you favour cannot doubt fuccels.</l>
	<l>Fred . This day I will begin to fetve thee in it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur .</speaker>
	<l> Sir,’twill be difficult to get access to her,</l>
	<l>Her Father is an humerousold man.</l>
	<l>And has his fits of Pride and kindness too-</l>
	<l>Fred . Well after dinner I will try my power.</l>
	<l>And will not quit his Lodgings till I’ve won him. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur .</speaker>
	<l> I humbly thank you Sir.</l>
	<l>Fred . Come let us haft, the day comes on apace. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur .</speaker>
	<l> I'le wait upon you Sir 5</l>
	<l>Oh, Cloris , thou’rtundone, falfe Amorous Girle 5 [_Ex. Fred.</l>
	<l>Was it for this I bred thee in obfcurity.</l>
	<l>Without permitting thee to know what Courts meant,</l>
	<l>Left their too powerful temptation</l>
	<l>Might have betray’d thy Soul 5</l>
	<l>Not fufferingtheeto know thy Name or Parents,</l>
	<l>Thinking an humble life</l>
	<l>Might have fecur’d thy Vertue:</l>
	<l>And yet I fhould not hate 'thee for this fin.</l>
	<l>Since thou art bred in fo much innocence, !</l>
	<l>Thou couldft not dream of falfity in men:</l>
	<l>Oh that it were permitted me to kill this Prince,</l>
	<l>This falfe perfidious Prince}</l>
	<l>And yet he knows hot that hehas abus’d me.</l>
	<l>When did I know a man of fo much Vertue,</l>
	<l>That</l>
	<l>That would refufe fofweet and (oft a Maid 5</l>
	<l>-—No he is juft and good only too much milled</l>
	<l>, By youth and flattery 5</l>
	<l>And one to whom my Soul is ty’d by friendlhip</l>
	<l>—Yet what’s a Friend, a name above a Sifter ></l>
	<l>Is not her Honour mine ></l>
	<l>And (hall not I revenge the 1q(s of it ></l>
	<l> It is but common Juftice.</l>
	<l>But firft I’le try all gentle means I may,</l>
	<l>And let him know that, is my Sifter 5</l>
	<l>And if he then perfevere in his crime.</l>
	<l>Fie lay my interft and my duty by,</l>
	<l>Andpunifti him, or with my Honour dye. Q Exit.</l>
	<l>SCENE III.</l>
	<l>The Apartment 0/Antonio.</l>
	<l>Enter Lorenzo pulling in of Isabella.</l>
	<l>4</l>
	<l>, Lor. Nay, nay, Isabella , there’s no avoiding me now :</l>
	<l>v You and I muft come to apfrley.</l>
	<l>Pray what’s the reafon</l>
	<l>You took no notice of me,</l>
	<l>WhepI came with fo civil anaddresstoo.</l>
	<l>I fab.. Can you ever think to thrive in an Amour,</l>
	<l>r When you take notice of your Miftress,</l>
	<l>Or any that belongs to herein publlque,</l>
	<l>And when (he’s a Married woman too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Good Isabella , the ldfer may have leave to Ipeak,</l>
	<l>vl. am fure it has been a plaguy dear Amour tome. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Let me hear you name that again,</l>
	<l>'11 Ut'L I v.:</l>
	<l> f h</l>
	<l>And you.(hall miss of my affiftance. : - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Nay, dobuthea me alittljal rng</l>
	<l>J vow ’tist.he ftrangeft thing in the world,</l>
	<l>A man muft part from lo much money as I have done-5</l>
	<l>And be confin’d to Signs and Crimmafles only, VOf ,</l>
	<l>To declare his mind in j , , —m;</l>
	<l>/ » 11 -» l . '</l>
	<l>i ii-i 'din</l>
	<l> A « 1 I ft</l>
	<l>J J / ivf.</l>
	<l>V.</l>
	<l> I t </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>o a .</speaker>
	<l> ti ,</l>
	<l>< 9 ) .</l>
	<l>If a man has a Tongue, let him exercife it, I fay,</l>
	<l>As long as he pays for (peaking. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Again with your paying fort 31 fee you are not</l>
	<l>To be reclaim’d 5 farewel— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Stay good Isabella , flay,</l>
	<l>And thou (halt here not one word of that more.</l>
	<l>Though I am foundly urg’d to’t.</l>
	<l>Ifab . Yes, yes, pray count them, do 3</l>
	<l>I know you long to be at it,</l>
	<l>And lamfureyou will find you are in Arrears to us. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Say you fo, I am not of that opinion, but well,</l>
	<l>—Let me fee—here ’tis, here ’tis—</l>
	<l>—My Bill of charge for Courting Clarina .</l>
	<l>[Draws out his Table Eook and reads. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> And here’s mine for the returns that have been</l>
	<l>Made you 3 begin, begin. [Pulls out her Book,. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Item , 200 Crowns to Ifibella for undertaking. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifib.</speaker>
	<l> Item , I have promis’d Lorenzo tofervejiim</l>
	<l>In his Amour with all fidelity. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Well, I own that debt paid, if you keep</l>
	<l>Your word— out with it then— [He crojfes that out.</l>
	<l>Item , 2000 Crowns in a Bracelet for Clarina 3</l>
	<l>What fay you to that now Isabella .? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifib.</speaker>
	<l> Item , The day after they were prefented.</l>
	<l>She faluted you with a fmile at the ChappeL </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> And doft thou think it was not dearly bought? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> 'No man in Florence fhould have haa it</l>
	<l>A Souce cheaper. ' \ + </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Say you fo Isabella 3 outjlfcdth it then. [Crojfes it out. </l>
	<l>Item , 100 more to thee for prefentingthem. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Which I did with fix lyes in your commendation,</l>
	<l>Worth ten Piftols a piece for the exactness of a Lie 3</l>
	<l>Write there indebted to me— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Tor.</speaker>
	<l> Nay then thou doft deferve it:</l>
	<l>Reft due to Isabella.  [ Writes.</l>
	<l>Item , Innumerable Serenades, night-walks, affronts</l>
	<l>And fears 3 and laftly, to the Poets for Songs, and the like. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Jfab.</speaker>
	<l> All which was recompenced in the exceflive</l>
	<l>. C Laughing</l>
	<l>C l °) \ ...</l>
	<l>Laughing on you that day you praunc’d under our</l>
	<l>Window on Horfe-back, when you madefucha</l>
	<l>Deal of Capriol and Curvet. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Yes, where I ventur’d my neck to (hew my</l>
	<l>Activity, and therefore may be well accompted</l>
	<l>Amongft my Ioffes.</l>
	<l>Ifiib. Thenfhe receiv’d your Prefents,</l>
	<l>Suffer’d your Serenades, without fending her footmeft</l>
	<l>To break your Pate with the Fiddles. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Indeed that was one of the beffc figns.</l>
	<l>For I have been a great fufferer in that kind</l>
	<l>Upon the like occafions} but doff thou think</l>
	<l>In confcience that this (hould fatisfie > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifib.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, any reafonable man in the world for the</l>
	<l>Firftmonth atleaff, and yet you are (till up</l>
	<l>Withyour expences, as if a Lady of her quality</l>
	<l>Were to be gain’d without them—</l>
	<l>Let me hear of your expences more, and I’le—- </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Oh fweet Tfabellu ! upon my knees,</l>
	<l>I beg thou wilt take no fatal refolution}</l>
	<l>For I proteft, as I am a man of Honour,</l>
	<l>And adore thy Sex, thou (halt only fee,</l>
	<l>Not hear of my expences more ;</l>
	<l>And for a fmall teftimony of it, here, take this </l>
	<l>There’s twenty Piffolsupon reputation. [ Gives her Money</l>
	<l>ifitb. Fie, Fie,’tis not brave, nor generous to name</l>
	<l>The fum 3 you (hould have Aid it into my coat,</l>
	<l>Without faying what you had done. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> What fignifies that mun, as long as’tis currant.</l>
	<l>And you have it fure. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifib.</speaker>
	<l> Well, leave the management of your Affairs to me,</l>
	<l>—What (hall we do ? here’s Alberto.</l>
	<l>Enter Alberto. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Igr.</speaker>
	<l> Well, who can help it $ I cannot walk invifible. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Lorenzo , what making Love to Isabella ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lc>r.</speaker>
	<l> kShe’l fervg, my Lord', for want of a better. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifib.</speaker>
	<l> That’s but a courfe Complement. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> ’Twill fervetodilguifeatruth however; f Aftde to her.</l>
	<l>Faith</l>
	<l>Faith Tie tell you. Sir, twas fuch another Damfel [Fx. ifab;</l>
	<l>As this, that lav’d me 500 pound once upon a time 5</l>
	<l>And I have lov’d the whole Tribe of Waiting-women</l>
	<l>The better ever fince. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> You have reafon, how was it > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Why look you Sir ></l>
	<l>I had made love a long time to a Lady,</l>
	<l> But fhe fhall be nameless.</l>
	<l>Since fhe was of a quality not tq be gain’d under</l>
	<l>The afbrefaid fum 5 well, I brought it.</l>
	<l>Came powder’d and perfum’d, and high in expectatioii. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Well Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> And (he had a very prety wench, who was to</l>
	<l>Conduft me, and in the dark too 5</l>
	<l>And on my confidence, I e’ne fell aboard of her.</l>
	<l>And was as well accommodated for my five.</l>
	<l>As five hundred pounds, and fo return’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> A great defeat to the Lady the while a my word. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> I, fhe fmelt the Plot, and made a vow to follow</l>
	<l>The Italian mode for the future,</l>
	<l>And be ferv’d in affairs of that kind,by none.</l>
	<l>But an old Woman. > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> ’Twas wittily refolv’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Are you for the prefence this morning } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> No, I have bufiness herewith Antonio. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Your Servant my Lord- Exit. Lorenzo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I do not like this fellows being here.</l>
	<l>The moft notorious Pimp, and Rafcal in Italy j</l>
	<l>’Tis a vile fhame that fuch as he fhould live.</l>
	<l>Who have the form and fenfe of man about them.</l>
	<l>And in their action Beaft,</l>
	<l>And that he thrives by too: Enter IfabdU.</l>
	<l>—Isabellas is Antonio Hiring? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Heis, pleafeyourLordfhipto walk in. . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> You may tell him I wait here—</l>
	<l>—Fori would avoid all opportunity of feeing C Ur in a. \_Ajlde. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifab.</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, you need not ftand upon Ceremonies.</l>
	<l>[Ex, Alberto.</l>
	<l>C 2 Enter</l>
	<l>( «2 )</l>
	<l>Enter Clarina and Kmendrejl like one another in-etiery thing.,</l>
	<l>Laughing and beholding one another:</l>
	<l>—Dreft already ! now on my confcience</l>
	<l>I know not which is which 3</l>
	<l>Pray God Antonio be notmiftaken at night,</l>
	<l>For I’]e be fworn I am by day-light. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Doft think I may pass thus for clarina ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, you are the fame to a hair.</l>
	<l>Wood I might never frit.</l>
	<l>If I can do any thingbut wonder. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> But hark Isabella 3 ifthoufhould’ft have</l>
	<l>Heard amiss, and that thy information (houId not be good.</l>
	<l>Thou haft defeated us of a defign,</l>
	<l>Wherein we promife our felves no little pleafure. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm .</speaker>
	<l> Yes I vow, all the Jeft is loft if it be fo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> I doubt ’twill be a true Jeft on your fide. [Apde.</l>
	<l>—I warrant you. Madam, my Intelligence is good 3</l>
	<l>And toaffureyou of what I have faid,</l>
	<l>I dare undertake you (hall hear the fame over again 3</l>
	<l>For juft now Alberto iscometo vifitmy Lord,</l>
	<l>Who I am fure will entertain him with no other ftories.</l>
	<l>But thofe of his jealoufie.</l>
	<l>And to perfwade him to Court you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tis ftrange, fince he fet him that task fo long ago,..</l>
	<l>H e would not begin before. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Nay, pray God he begin now </l>
	<l>Sifter, he has hitherto took me for thee,</l>
	<l>And fometimes his eyes give me hope ofa fecret </l>
	<l>Fire within, but ’twill not out 3</l>
	<l>And I am fo impatient till he declares himfelf,</l>
	<l>That if he do not do it foon, ,</l>
	<l>Hball e’ne tell hinrwho I am 5</l>
	<l>11 i i</l>
	<l>, y, \</l>
	<l>I For perhaps, the Wife takes off the appetite' </l>
	<l>\ Which would (harpen upon knowledge of the Virgin. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> What then, you’l have all the fpprt to your felf 5 ,</l>
	<l>—But, Ifnena , remember my little revenge on Antonio</l>
	<l>Muft</l>
	<l>( 1 3 )</l>
	<l>Muft accompany your love to Alberto. [ Afide </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> But why this refemblance ></l>
	<l>For, Madam, fince he never faw you.</l>
	<l>And takes Ifmena to be you 3</l>
	<l>Might you not ftillpass fo, without this likeness ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> Didft thoumot fay, Antonio left the Court</l>
	<l>And City, on purpofe to give Albertothe more freedom</l>
	<l>To Court me :</l>
	<l>—Whilft he was away, I needed but retire.</l>
	<l>And Ifmena appear, and ’twould fufficee 3</l>
	<l>But now he is return’d,</l>
	<l>He may chance to lee them together, en pafant, or fo,</l>
	<l>And this dress will abufe him as well as Alberto ,</l>
	<l>For without that, this Plot of oursfignifies little. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Aye truly for my part, I have no other defign</l>
	<l>Then doing my Sifter a fervice. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> The Plot is very likely to thrive I fee.</l>
	<l>Since you are fo good at diflembling. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Fie Isabella , what an ill opinion you have of me?</l>
	<l>—But Sifter,’tis much Alberto being fo intimate</l>
	<l>W ith Antonio , (hould never lee you all this whole</l>
	<l>Six months of your being Marti edl </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> Had you been bred any where.</l>
	<l>But in a Monaftery, you would have known, '</l>
	<l>’Tis not the cuftom here for mentofexpofe their'</l>
	<l>Wives to the. view of any, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> I hear them coming, let’s away,</l>
	<l>Anaprayliften to the truths! have aTready’told you. [Exe>.</l>
	<l>SCENE. IV.</l>
	<l>Enter Antonio Mil "Alberto.</l>
	<l> ; .mi/: x'-na 1 won vhv.-W   -r ! .</l>
	<l>, „ . [Clarina and Ifmena liften. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Once more Antonio , welcom back to Court.</l>
	<l>thy embraces 3</l>
	<l>to play } \</l>
	<l>rhdi </l>
	<l>Albo </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Oh my dear friend, I long’d for</l>
	<l>—How goes the Game I left w'ith thee</l>
	<l>What fays my 1 Wife, my beautiful Clar,</l>
	<l>( (4)</l>
	<l>" t \ ' A  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Clarina-- </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Yes daring have you not feen her yet ></l>
	<l>I left the Court on purpofe, for ’twas not handfome</l>
	<l>For me to introduce you j</l>
	<l>Left (he had lookt upon’t as fome defign. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Seen her—yes—-  .  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> And I conjur’d her too, to give you freedoms</l>
	<l>Even equal to Antonio j</l>
	<l>As far as I durft prels with modefty.</l>
	<l>And with pretence of Friepdlhip $</l>
	<l>And have you not attempted her ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Yes— but ’tis in vain. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Villanious diflembler. [ \Ajide, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> She’s cruel, ftrangely cruel.</l>
	<l>And I’me refolv’d to give the Courtfhip o’re. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Sure friend, thou haft not us’d thy wonted power. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, all that I knew I’me mafter of, I us’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> But didft thou urge it home ? did fhe not fee.</l>
	<l>Thy words and aftions did not well agree?</l>
	<l>.Canftthou diftemble well? dicjftcryand melt.</l>
	<l>As if the pain you but expreft, yOufelt? . ,</l>
	<l>Didft kneel, and fwear, and urge thy quality,</l>
	<l>Heightning it too with fome diigrace on me ?</l>
	<l>And didft thou too aflail her feeble fide ?</l>
	<l>For the beft bait to woman is her Pride 5</l>
	<l>Which fome mifieall her Guard;</l>
	<l>Didft thou prefent her with the fett of Jewels?</l>
	<l>For Women naturally are more inclin’d</l>
	<l>To Avarice, then Men:</l>
	<l>Pray tell me Friend,</l>
	<l>—Vile woman did (he take them— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I never ask’d her-that </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> Poor Antonio how I pity him. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> NoL jry ; ’, rn </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> No, V ve done enough to fatisfie. thy jealoufie 5.</l>
	<l>Here take your fet of Jewels back again y ., j \Gives a Box .</l>
	<l>Upon niy life cUrina kail ; cb#ty j;,  3r ,,Q </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I were the happieftman.on Eari, were this, Jut truer r</l>
	<l>' v But</l>
	<l>\_Ajide.</l>
	<l>05 J)</l>
	<l>But what are (ingle Courtfhips— give her thefe</l>
	<l>Which will affid thy tongue to win her heart $</l>
	<l>And that once got, the other foon will follow $</l>
	<l>There’s far more women won by Gold then induftry:</l>
	<l>Try that my dear Alberto ,</l>
	<l>And fave thy eyes the trouble of defembling. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Content thee here, and do not tempt thy -fate,</l>
	<l>I have regard unto thy Honour Friend;,</l>
	<l>And fhould (he yield, as women are no gods.</l>
	<l>Where were thy future Joys 5</l>
	<l>What is’t could make thee happy, or redore</l>
	<l>That true contentment which thou had’d before?</l>
	<l>Alas thou tempt’d me too, for I am frail,</l>
	<l>And love above my friendflrip may prevail. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> This will not do 5</l>
	<l>No, as thou art my Friend, and lov’d my Honour,</l>
	<l>Purfue clarina further,</l>
	<l>Rally a frefli, and charge her with this Prefent,</l>
	<l>JDidurb her every night with Serenades </l>
	<l>Make Love-Songs to her, and then Sing them too 3</l>
	<l>Thou had a voice enough alone to conquer.</l>
	<l> Alb. Fool Antonio. £ Afide . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Come wilt thou undertake it once again ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I would not. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I am refolv’d to get this tryal made.</l>
	<l>And if thou doftrefufe thy Amity,</l>
	<l>lie try a Friend more willing, though less faithful.</l>
	<l>With thee my Wife and Honour too are fafe 5</l>
	<l>Forlhouldftie y ield, and I by that were Iod,</l>
	<l>’Twere yet fome eafe.</l>
	<l>That none but thou wer’t witness to’t. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Well, if it mud be done. I’de rather do’c.</l>
	<l>Then you thould be expos’d to th’ fcorn of others. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Spoke like my noble Friend }</l>
	<l>Come dine with her to day, for I mud leave you.</l>
	<l>And give you all the opportunity</l>
	<l>A real Lover wifhes with a MiftreG:</l>
	<l>\_lfim. So we have heard enough. J £x.Clar ( . and'lfftu </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Oh were Clarina chade, as on my Soul I</l>
	<l>I cannot doubt, more then that I believe</l>
	<l>All womankind may be (educ’d from Vertue 5</l>
	<l>I were the man of all the world mod bled.</l>
	<l>In fuch a Wife, and fuch a Friend as thou. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> But what if I prevail Antonio > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Then Tie renounce my faith in woman kind,</l>
	<l>And place my iatisfaction in thy Amity.</l>
	<l>—But fee fhe comes,1’le leave you to your task.</l>
	<l>Enter Ifmena and Isabella. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio not yet gone—</l>
	<l>This mud fecure me. ; > Tulls down her Veil , </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Clarina 0 -. why thus clouded ></l>
	<l>Ifab . I fee he has mod happily midaken. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> I was going, Sir 3 to vifit Laura— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> You mud not go, I’ve bufiness to the Duke,</l>
	<l>And you mud entertain my Friend till my return 5</l>
	<l>It is a freedom not ufual here amongd Ladies,</l>
	<l>But I will have it fo V</l>
	<l>Whom I edeem I’le have you dofo to. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, I am all obedience.</l>
	<l>, [Exit Antonio, she pulls offher Veil’j Albert, flutes her</l>
	<l>with fieming-lowness. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Oh how my Soul’s divided,</l>
	<l>.Between my Adoration and my Amity !</l>
	<l>-Friendfhip, thou facred band, hold fad thy intered,</l>
	<l>For yonder Beauty has a fubtle power.</l>
	<l>And can undo that knot, which other Arts</l>
	<l>Could ne’re invent a way for.</l>
	<l>Enter A ntonio and liflens at the door. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Fie fee a little how he behaves himfelf. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> But die’s Antonio' s wife 5 my friend Antonio ,</l>
	<l>A youth that made an intered in my Soul,</l>
	<l>When Ihad Janguage fcarcetoexprelsmy fenfe of it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Death, hefpeaks not to her. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> So grew we up to man, and dill more fixt 5</l>
	<l>And (hall a gawdy beauty,</l>
	<l>A thing, which t’other day, I never (aw,</l>
	<l>Depri ve nvy heart of that kind heat.</l>
	<l>[Afde</l>
	<l>£ A fide.</l>
	<l>[\ A fide .</l>
	<l>[ \Afde .</l>
	<l>[Afide.</l>
	<l> Ad</l>
	<l>»</l>
	<l>(7)</l>
	<l>And place a new and unknown fire within 5</l>
	<l>Clarina , ’tisunjuft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifrt.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, did you (peak to me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> I have betray’d myfelf—</l>
	<l>Madam, I was faying how unjuft it was</l>
	<l>Antoniofhould leave me alone with a Lady,</l>
	<l>Being certainly the word to entertain them in the world. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> His face allures me he (peaks of no love to her now.</l>
	<l>Alas, he (peaks not to me, . [Afidc.</l>
	<l>Sure TJabella wasmiftaken.</l>
	<l>Who told me that he lov’d me 5</l>
	<l>—— Alberto , if thou art oblig’d to me,</l>
	<l>For what I have notyetobferv’d in thee ;</l>
	<l>Oh do not fay my heart was eafily won.</l>
	<l>But blame your eyes, whofe forces none can (bun. . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Not a word, what can he mean by this ?</l>
	<l>Ifnt . Sir, will you pleafe to fit awhile ?  ; ,., v . v</l>
	<l>Ifab . Madam, the inner chamber is much better,</l>
	<l>For there he may repofe upon the Cufiiions til] my</l>
	<l>Lords return 3 I fee he is not well—- '</l>
	<l> r> r</l>
	<l>t </l>
	<l> l) 1 (</l>
	<l>[Afide</l>
	<l>L ? >._ 1 ilQJ</l>
	<l> ‘ ‘ ih J ; I J > ; </l>
	<l>TElj 1</l>
	<l>il u</l>
	<l>[-Afide. </l>
	<l>J j- o'nor:; fud</l>
	<l>—And you are bothfickof one difeafe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I thank you, here’s more air,</l>
	<l>—And that I need, for I amallon firet „r. r _. . t _ r . r>nrt .</l>
	<l>And every look adds fuel to my Same. </l>
	<l>—Imuftavoid thofe eyes, whole light mifguides me :</l>
	<l>—Madam, I have (bme bufiness calls me hence, V</l>
	<l>Andcannot wait my friends return. ‘ (  0 .' . Vi </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifrt.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio , Sir, will think ’tis my negle££.  </l>
	<l>That drove you hence 5 pray ftay a’ little JongeY. J l ' c - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> You fhall command me, if yocan i(pence</l>
	<l>With fo dull company. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifab.</speaker>
	<l> I can with any thing Antonio loves. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, it is a</l>
	<l>For though your Hufbsad. ftejld nqt jt f -ricjiib</l>
	<l>Yourgoodness .snotkss feeai aE » llteidw</l>
	<l>But he s a man fo truely worth your Kinanels,</l>
	<l>That ’twere a fin to doubt, (</l>
	<l>Your paffionkf .ilim wys.pot</l>
	<l>ri ibfiaii’Kri nodi</l>
	<l>5?rol /Liidi no  oU .v.\ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifni.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, I believe you, and I hope he thinks</l>
	<l>That my opinion of him equals yours 5</l>
	<l>’Tis plain he loves me not, [Atde.</l>
	<l>Perhaps, his Vertue, thinking m eClarina,</l>
	<l>May hide the real paflion of his Soul.</l>
	<l>Oh Love, what dangerous paths thou mak’ft us tread f </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Cold;, cold as Devotion, oh inhumane friend(hip f </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Whatfhall Ido next? I muft either be rude.</l>
	<l>And fay nothing, or fpeak of Love to her 5</l>
	<l>And then my Friend thou’rt loft (hould I prevail,</l>
	<l>And I’me undone (hould (he not hear my tale.</l>
	<l>Which for the world I would not have her hear 5</l>
	<l>And yet I fear my eyes too much declare. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Since he’s info ill an humour, let’s leave him,</l>
	<l>Tme (atisfy’d now that thou wer’t miftaken.</l>
	<l>[E. Ifmena and Isabella unfeen. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> But they (hall gaze no more on hers.</l>
	<l>Nor ftray beyond the limits of a juft falute.</l>
	<l>—I will my Honour to my Love prefer,</l>
	<l>And my Antonio (hall out-R.ival her. [Looks about andmiffes thorn.</l>
	<l>— Ah, am I left alone how frail is man 5</l>
	<l>That which Iaft moment I refoly’d upon, .</l>
	<l>I find my heart already difappFote,</l>
	<l>And grieve her Ioss 5 can this be ought but love ></l>
	<l>My Sours diffatisfy'd now (he is gone.</l>
	<l>And yet but now I wifti’t to be alone 5</l>
	<l>M jry i t  < f . jjr - - _ « c >”'</l>
	<l>Enter Antonio "and'fiayshim. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Whether in</l>
	<l>Thou looked e’ne as fad as  Lover re</l>
	<l>r ,#J</l>
	<l>t iS L ?</l>
	<l>h a ji</l>
	<l>[Oflerstogo.</l>
	<l>i fear that fate’s, not thine. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Now for a fye n</l>
	<l>Prethee difchargeme ofii s toy I t)fyi 1 ftettfaji ng,. 1</l>
	<l>Of which I grow asyvearVi ifteV0f‘Jfearfng it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l>, Sure thou hafteadefignlxxmakeher hafeme  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Do you think fo in eartft, ‘wftjfwas fheangfy f</l>
	<l> \» ' y  ‘ ' /</l>
	<l>Alb </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Oh! hadftthou feen her pretty blufhing (corn</l>
	<l>Which fhe would fain havehtd; </l>
	<l>Thou wouldft have pitied what I made her fuffer. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Is’tpoflible 1</l>
	<l>And didftprefent her with the Box of Jewels ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Yes. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> And kneel, and cry, and fwear, and—. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> All, all. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I hardly gave thee time for fo much Courtfhip.</l>
	<l>—But you are lure fhe was dilpleafed with it } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Extremely. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Enough Alberto? adieu totheeandfriendfhip. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> What mean you } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Ask your own guilt, it will inform thee bed. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Thou canft not think cUrina has abus’d thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I do not think Che has, nor have y on try’d her;</l>
	<l>In that you have not only difbblig’d me.</l>
	<l>But now you would impofeupon my weaknefc 7</l>
	<l>—Did I not fee how unconcern’d you were.</l>
	<l>And hardly paying her a due refpect 5</l>
	<l>And when fhe even invited thee to (peak.</l>
	<l>Mod rudely thou wer’t filent. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Be calm Antonio , Iconfessmy error.</l>
	<l>And hate that vertue taught me to deceave thee $</l>
	<l>—Here take my hand,—</l>
	<l>Fie ferve thee in good earned. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> And now I do believe thee,</l>
	<l>Go—thou (halt lofe no time, I mud away.</l>
	<l>My Soul’s in torment, tell I am confirm’d</l>
	<l>Of my Clarinas Vertue 5</l>
	<l>I dobelievethou had a generous fhame.</l>
	<l>For what thou’d faid ana done to me thy friend 7</l>
	<l>For could I doubt thy love . oh how ridiculous</l>
	<l>This a ct of mine would feem!</l>
	<l>But ’tis to thee, as to my Soul I come,</l>
	<l>Difputing every petty crime and doubt. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio if there need an Oath between us. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> No, I credit thee 3 go in,</l>
	<l>D 2</l>
	<l>(so)</l>
	<l>And prethee drefe thy eyes in all their Charms,</l>
	<l>For this uncertainty difturbsme more.</l>
	<l>Then if I knew Clarina were a—Whore— [Exeunt feverallj. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ACT.</speaker>
	<l> II. SCENE. I...</l>
	<l>The Apartment 0/Frederick.</l>
	<l></l>
	<l>Enter Frederick with a Letter , and Galliard.</l>
	<l>Ot allow me to fpeak to her, fay ye, Yts ftrange 5</l>
	<l>jL\| Did’ft fay it was the Prince that fent thee ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ser .</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, I did, but he fays, he cares not for</l>
	<l>A thoufimd Princes.</l>
	<l>Fred . I am refolv’d I will fee this woman 5 </l>
	<l>—Harkey, go back again and fay— - [whifpers.</l>
	<l>Enter Lorenzo Drunk; </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Hah the Prince—hemuft not fee me</l>
	<l>In this pickle 5 for I would not lofe my reputation</l>
	<l>Of Wenching, for this of Dririkings</l>
	<l>And I am fure I cannot be excellent at both,</l>
	<l>They are inconfiftent.  ,,, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ser.</speaker>
	<l> Ifhallmy Lord. [Ex. Galliard. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Your HighnesshumbleTervaut. , </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Ha, ha, what Lorenzo in deboach. - ; : </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Now my tongue will betray me j</l>
	<l>—Faith 5 my Lord, I have took fix, but am come briskly off 5.</l>
	<l>By th‘19 hand, my Lord, I am cock over five.</l>
	<l>Stout Rogues too ,-1 can tell you, at this fpott : v </l>
	<l>JFred . I did not think thou hadft had that Vertue. ' - , </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Fletell you, Sir, Yis neceflTary thofeofmy</l>
	<l>Office and quality, (hould have more Vertues</l>
	<l>Thenoneto recommend them 5  ; , - >;</l>
	<l>But to tell you truth, for now I am moft apt for that, A</l>
	<l>I was drunk in meer malice to day.</l>
	<l>j ,   - -  1  - . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>( 21 ) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Malice, againfl: whom prethee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Why, why, Sir, the humorous old fellow</l>
	<l>My Father, he will not hear reafon from me when I am fober. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Why, what’s the matter between you ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, you know Curtins is an honeft fellow.</l>
	<l>And one of us too 5</l>
	<l>My lifter Laura is a good pifetty Wench,</l>
	<l>He loves her, and fhe likes him 3</l>
	<l>And becaufethis tefty old Blade has done himfelf.</l>
	<l>Do you think I can bring him to confider }</l>
	<l>No not for my life he wont confider Sir $</l>
	<l>And now am I got drunk to fee how that will edifie him. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> How! is Laura the Miftriss of Curtins your lifter } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Yes marry is (he Sir, at leaft by the Mothers fide j</l>
	<l>And to tell you truth,</l>
	<l>We are too good natur’d to believe</l>
	<l>Salvator our Father. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Thy Sifter and Daughter to Salvator ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> So laid my Mother, but Ihe was handfom,</l>
	<l>And on my confcience liv’d, e’en in fuch another ,</l>
	<l>Debaucht world as ’tis now 5 let them fay</l>
	<l>What they will oftheir Primitive vertue. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> May not I fee this Sifter of thine Lorenzo ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Yeby Venus (hall your Sir,</l>
	<l>And (he were my Mother. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> But art fure thy Father will permit us ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> My Father permit us!</l>
	<l>He may do what he will when I am fober, J</l>
	<l>But being thus fortify’d with potent Wine, \</l>
	<l>He muft yield obedience to my will 5</l>
	<l>Why my Lord, Tie tell yon 3</l>
	<l> lle make him ask me blefling when I am in this</l>
	<l>Almighty power. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> And is thy Sifter fo very fine ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> The Girl is well, and if Ihe were not my Sifter,</l>
	<l>I would give you a more certain proof of my '</l>
	<l>Opinion of her 3 </l>
	<l>She has excellent good Hair, fine Teeth, - ,</l>
	<l>‘ And</l>
	<l>.'-(??) ' </l>
	<l>% And good bands, and thebcfl: natnr’d FooL, ,</l>
	<l>-Come, come, Sir, Tie bring you to her</l>
	<l> And then He leave you 5</l>
	<l>For I have a fmall affair of Love to difpatch. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> This is a freedom that futes not with the</l>
	<l>Humour of an Italian. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> No faith, my Lord, I believe my' Mother play’d</l>
	<l>Foul play withfome Englijh man 5</l>
	<l>I am fo willingtodoyou a good office to my Sifter,</l>
	<l>And if by her humour you become of that opinion too,</l>
	<l>I (hall hope to render my felf more acceptable</l>
	<l>To you by that Franchife.</l>
	<l>Enter Galliard, whifpers. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Thou knoweft my grateful temper,,</l>
	<l>—Nomatter 5 here carry this Letter to Clork,</l>
	<l>And make fome excufe for my not coming this evening.</l>
	<l>Gives him a Letter, and goes out with Lorenz </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ser.</speaker>
	<l> So, poor Lass, ’tis a hundred to one if (he be not</l>
	<l>Lay’d by now, and Laura muft fucceed her:</l>
	<l>Well, even Frederic 4 , I fee, is but a man,</l>
	<l>. But his youth and quality will excufe him 5</l>
	<l>And ’twill be called gallantry in him,</l>
	<l>I When in one of us, J tis ill nature and inconftancy.</l>
	<l>%  —.    1</l>
	<l>SCENE IL</l>
	<l>.Enter Ifmena and Isabella.</l>
	<l>' ‘ , «;«# 9</l>
	<l>' ’   . f # f </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Nay, Madam, ti$ in vain to deny it,</l>
	<l>, Do you think I have liv-d to thefe years,</l>
	<l>And cannot interpret Croft Arms, imperfed replies</l>
	<l>/ Your fudden weepings, your often fighing,</l>
	<l>1 Your melancholy walks, and making Verles top ?</l>
	<l>V And yet I mud: not fay that this is Love. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ijm.</speaker>
	<l> A rt thou fo notable a Judge of it > , </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> I (hould be, or lam a very dull Schollar,</l>
	<l>For I have loft the fooli(h boy as many Darts,</l>
	<l>As any W oman of my age in Florence .</l>
	<l>C 2 3 ) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Thou haftpay’d dear for thy knowledge then. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> No, the hurts one did.</l>
	<l>The other ftill made good with very little</l>
	<l>Pain on either fide. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> I muft confess, I think it is not (o hard to get ?</l>
	<l>Wounds, as'tis to get them cur'd again. - J</l>
	<l>Ifab . Iam not of your opinion, nor ever faw that</l>
	<l>Man that had not faults to Cure,</l>
	<l>As well as charms to kill. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm .</speaker>
	<l> Since thou’rtfo good a Judge of men,</l>
	<l>Prethee tell me how thou lik'd Alberto. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> I knew 'twould come to this— ' [ \Afide</l>
	<l>Why well Madam. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> No more then fo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Yes wondrous well, fince I am fure he loves you,</l>
	<l>And that indeed raifes a mans value. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Thou art deceiv'd, I do not think he Loves me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Madam,you cannot but fee a thoufand marks on’t. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Thou haft more skill then 1 </l>
	<l>But prethee why does he not tell me fo himfelf. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Madam! whilft he takes you for Clarina ,</l>
	<l>'Twould fhow his dif refpe<ft to tell his Love 3</l>
	<l>But when he knows Ifmena is the objeft,</l>
	<l>He’le tire you with the wifht for ftory. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Ah, thou art a pleafing flatterer.</l>
	<l>Enter page ♦ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Page.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, Alberto is without. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm .</speaker>
	<l> Tell him I’me indifpos’d, and cannot fee him now. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Nay, good Madam, fee him now by all means.</l>
	<l>For I am fure my Lord Antonio is abfent on pitrpofe $</l>
	<l>—Bid him come in Boy. Ex. Pager</l>
	<l>Enter Alberto. ‘ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio , Sir, is not return’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, this vifit was not meant to him.</l>
	<l>But by a caufe more preffing t am brought.</l>
	<l>Such as my paflion, not my friendflup taught</l>
	<l>A paffion which my fighs have only (hewn.</l>
	<l>And now beg leave my baftiful tongue may own</l>
	<l>rt  y</l>
	<l>( 24 )</l>
	<l>The knowledge.. Madam, will not much furprife.</l>
	<l>Which you have gain’d already from mine eyes3</l>
	<l>My timerous heart that way my tongue would (pare.</l>
	<l>And tells you of the flames you’ve kindled there:</l>
	<l>Tis long I’ve fuffer’d under this conftraint,</l>
	<l>Have always fuffer’d, but ne’re made complaint 3</l>
	<l>And now againd my will I mud reveal.</l>
	<l>What Love, and my refpett, would fain conceal. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> What mean you Sir ? what have you feen in me.</l>
	<l>That fhould encourage this temerity > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> A world of Beauties, and a world of Charms,</l>
	<l>And every fmile and frown begets new harms 3</l>
	<l>In vain I drove my paffion to fubdue.</l>
	<l>Which dill increas’d the more I look’t on you 3</l>
	<l>Nor will my heart permit me to retire,</l>
	<l>But makes my eyes the convoys to my fire.</l>
	<l>And not one glance you fend is cad away. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Enough my Lord,have you nought elfe to fay ? \jmiUs.</l>
	<l>The Plots betray’d, and can no further go 5</l>
	<l>The Stratagem’s difcover’d to the Foej</l>
	<l>I find Antonio has more dove then wit,</l>
	<l>And Lie endeavour too to merit it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> What you have faid, Ido confess is true,</l>
	<l>Antonio beg’d I would make love to you 5</l>
	<l>But, Madam, whild my heart was unconfin’d,</l>
	<l>A thoufand ways the treachery I declin’d 3</l>
	<l>But now Clarina , by my life I fwear,</l>
	<l>It is my own concern that brings me here:</l>
	<l>Had he been judtoyoU, I had fuppred</l>
	<l>The flame your eyes have kindled in my bread 3</l>
	<l>But his fufpition rais’d my paffion more.</l>
	<l>And his injudice taught me adore 5</l>
	<l>But ’tis a paffion which you may allow , : :;? Vv .</l>
	<l>Since its effectsfhalLnever injure you.iv iiifL </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> You have oblig’d me, Sir, by yOkrconfeffian,</l>
	<l>.And I fhall own it too. at fnch a rate.</l>
	<l>As both becomes my duty to Antonio,</l>
	<l>And myrefipeft to you 3 but I mud beg 1 y - </l>
	<l>W(</l>
	<l>)V 01 ’</l>
	<l>You’l</l>
	<l>Afide v</l>
	<l>: inJ f,' ;</l>
	<l>Tonal unerer cj«e jmt pgfEKXs rome more 3 ;</l>
	<l>That guilty language, Sir ,1 muff not hear,,</l>
	<l>—A nd' y et your filence kills me.</l>
	<l>\_lfib. Very well diffembled. |Jjftdev </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Tcan obey you. Madam, though l cannot live,</l>
	<l>Whilft you command me filence 3</l>
	<l>For ’tis aflame that dares not look abroad</l>
	<l>Tofeek for pity from anothers eyes. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifni.</speaker>
	<l> How he moves me 3 if this were real now,</l>
	<l>Or that he knew to whom he made this Courtftiip— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Oh do not turn away as ifdifpleas’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> No more, you’ve difcompos’d my thoughts 3</l>
	<l>Begon and never let me fee thy face again. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, I go, and will no more offend you,</l>
	<l>—-But I will look my laft—farewel. [fff ers t 0 gP </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>IJab.</speaker>
	<l> Pray, Madam, call him back, he may be defperate.</l>
	<l>—My Lord return— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Alberto , tell me what you’d have me dov </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Ah Madam, do not put me to my choice.</l>
	<l>For Lovers are unreafonable,</l>
	<l>If I might name it, I would have you love me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Love you, and what would be the end of that ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I cannot tell, butwiffi you were inclin’d</l>
	<l>Tomakeatryal, Madam 3</l>
	<l>I have no thought or wifh beyond that bleffiag.</l>
	<l>And that once gain’d lure, I fhould ask no more. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Were I inclin’d to this, have you contider’d</l>
	<l>The fatal confequences which attend</l>
	<l>The breach of Vows and Friendfhip. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, Antonio fir ft was falfeto you,</l>
	<l>And not topunifh that, were fuch a Vertue</l>
	<l>As he would never thank you for 3</l>
	<l>By all that’s good, till he prov’d fo to you.</l>
	<l>He had my Soul in keeping 3</l>
	<l>But this aft, makes me refolve</l>
	<l>To recompence his folly. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> You’ve found the eafieft paffage to my heart, }</l>
	<l>Y ou’ve took it on the weakeft fide 3 j</l>
	<l>E</l>
	<l>But</l>
	<l>—But I muft beg you will pretend no further. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Divine Clarina , let me pay my thanks</l>
	<l>In this fubmiflive poflure, and never rife, £ Kneels .</l>
	<l>Till I can gain fomuch upon your credit.</l>
	<l>As to believe my paffion tends no farther</l>
	<l>Then to adore you thus-— and thus poffessyou,</l>
	<l>[_KiJfis her hand and Bows.</l>
	<l>If nt. Have not 1 diflembled finely Isabella. [_Afide. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifab.</speaker>
	<l> - Yes, if you could make me believe ’tis fo. [A fide . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifit.</speaker>
	<l> Rife, Sir, and leave me, that I may bluCh alone</l>
	<l>For what I’ve parted with fo eafily 5</l>
	<l>Pray do not vifit me again too foon,</l>
	<l>—But ufe your own difcretion, and befecret: </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, The bleffed fecret here is lodg’d.</l>
	<l>Which time (hall ne’re reveal to humane knowledge. [' Ex. Alb. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifin.</speaker>
	<l> I’me glad he’s gone before Antonio return’d 3</l>
	<l>Enter Laura Weeping.</l>
	<l>—What Laura all in Tears, the reafon pray ! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, the Prince conduced by my brother, ></l>
	<l>About an hour fince made me a vifit 5</l>
	<l>The Man of all the world I would havefhun’d.</l>
	<l>Knowing his Amorous and inconflant temper 3</l>
	<l>— At his approach he blufht and flatted back.</l>
	<l>And I with great amazement did the like.</l>
	<l>With fear I loft all power of going from him,</l>
	<l>As he had done of making his address 3</l>
	<l>He gaz’d, and wonder’d, and [ gaz’d on him.</l>
	<l>And from his filence I became amaz’d.</l>
	<l>—My brother flood confounded at our pollutes,-</l>
	<l>And only by the motion of his head,</l>
	<l>(Which now he turn’d to me, then on the Prince)</l>
	<l>Weknew that he had life. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifni.</speaker>
	<l> Well, how recover’d ye> </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> The Prince then kneel’d, but could approach no nearer.</l>
	<l>And then asif he’d taken mefor fome Deity 3</l>
	<l>He made a long diforder’d Amorous fpeech,</l>
	<l>Which brought me back to fenfe again 3</l>
	<l>But Lorenzo told him that I was a mortaI 3</l>
	<l>And</l>
	<l>" ' (t)</l>
	<l>And brought him nearer to me.</l>
	<l>Where he began to make liich vows of Love—</l>
	<l>Ifru What then ?</l>
	<l>Lm. Then I am ruin’d— .</l>
	<l>To all [ faid he found a contradiction.</l>
	<l>And my denials did but more inflame him $</l>
	<l>I told him of the vowsl’de made to Curtin %</l>
	<l>But he reply’d that Curtins was a Subject 3</l>
	<l>But fure at laft I’de won upon his goodnels.</l>
	<l>Had not my Father enter’d.</l>
	<l>To whom the Prince addreft himfelfj</l>
	<l>And with his moving tale fo won upon him.,</l>
	<l>Or rather by his quality</l>
	<l>That he has gain’d his leave to vifit me,</l>
	<l>And quite forbids me e’re to fpeak to Cnrtim. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Alas the day, is this all? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> All? can there be more to make me miferable? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm .</speaker>
	<l> I lee noreafon thou haft to complain 3</l>
	<l>Come, wipe your eyes, and take a good heart,</l>
	<l>For Ile tell thee a ftory of my own.</l>
	<l>That will let thee lee I have much more caufe to weep 3</l>
	<l>And yet I have a thouland little ftratagems</l>
	<l>In my head, which give me as many hopes:</l>
	<l>This unlucky reftraint upon our Sex,</l>
	<l>Makes us all cunning, and that lhall affift thee now</l>
	<l>With my help, I warrant thee 3</l>
	<l>Come in with me and know the reft. [Exeunt, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> So, lo, dilguife it how you will,</l>
	<l>I know you are a real Lover 3</l>
	<l>And that lecret lhall advance my Love-delign 3</l>
	<l>Yes Madam, now I will be ferv’d by you.</l>
	<l>Or you (hall fail to find a friend of me. [Ex. Ifob</l>
	<l>E 2</l>
	<l>SCENE.</l>
	<l>Cs> </l>
	<l>SCENE Iff.</l>
	<l>Enter Lorenzo Drttn 4, with a Page , //«/?< 4 as in the dari f .</l>
	<l>Lor, Here’s the door, begin and play yourbeft.</l>
	<l>But let them be foft low Notes, do you hear > (“TJctfj Pity</l>
	<l>Enter Antonio. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Mufick at my Lodgings, it is Alberto b</l>
	<l>Oh how Ilovehimfor’t—i iclarina ftandhis</l>
	<l>Courtfhip, lam made? </l>
	<l>I languid] between hbpe and fear. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Stay Friend, I hear fome body. ceajes. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Page.</speaker>
	<l> Tisnobody Sir.</l>
	<l>Enter Tfabella. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifib.</speaker>
	<l> 5 Tis Lorenzo , and my Plots ripe b</l>
	<l>9 T will not fure be hard to get him, under pretence</l>
	<l>Of feeing Clarina into my Chamber,</l>
	<l>And then I’le order him at my pleafure :</l>
	<l>ifmena is on my fide, fori know all her fecrets,</l>
	<l>And (he muft wink at mine therefore. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Thou art in the right Boy,</l>
	<l>I think indeed ’twas nothing.</l>
	<l>[A fide.</l>
	<l>Lorenzo being</l>
	<l>retir'd the white</l>
	<l>a little further.-</l>
	<l>[[she retires.</l>
	<l>‘ 'f/'f f T C" r i</l>
	<l>[flitys again.</l>
	<l>Enter Albertol </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> She yields, bad woman!</l>
	<l> Why fo eafily won?</l>
	<l>By me too, who am thy Husbands friend : : . r !</l>
	<l>Oh dangerous boldness! uncconfidering woman,</l>
	<l>I lov’d thee, whilftl thought thou could’ft notyield 5</l>
	<l>But now that eafiness has undone thy intereft in my heart: </l>
	<l>Lie back and tell thee that it was to try thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> No, no, ’twas my fears, away with the Song,</l>
	<l>Fie take it on your word that ’tis fit for my purpofe.</l>
	<l>- fid . Lie warrant you my Lord. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Song.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>fow a:</l>
	<l>I N vain I have labour'd the Victor to prove ,</l>
	<l>Of a heart that can ne re give attendance to Love i</l>
	<l>So hard to be done ,</l>
	<l>That nothing fo young</l>
	<l>Could ere have refljled a pajjion fo long.</l>
	<l>Tet nothing I left unattempted or foid ,</l>
	<l>That might foften the heart of this pitiless Maid : j</l>
	<l>But Jlill foe was foye 0</l>
	<l>And would blufljing deny ,</l>
	<l>Whiljl her willinger eyes gave her Language the lye.</l>
	<l>Since Phillis., my pajjion you vow to defpifo ,</l>
	<l>Withdraw the falfo hopes from your flattering eyes ,</l>
	<l>For whilji they infpire</l>
	<l>Areflfiless vain fire.</l>
	<l>We fl) all grow to abhor , what we now do admire. [T.. Muflck' </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> What’s this, and at Clarinas lodgings too ?</l>
	<l>Sure tis Antonio impatient of delay-,</l>
	<l>Gives her a Serenade for me.</l>
	<l>Enter Isabella. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifob.</speaker>
	<l> 'Tis the fool himfelf—</l>
	<l>My Lord, where are you ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> How, a womans voice! 3 tis dark, Tie advance. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Thou Simpleton, I told thee there was (ome-body. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Pag.</speaker>
	<l> Lord, Sir, W%on\y Isabella that calls you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Away Sirrah, I find by my fears tis no woman, ,</l>
	<l>[Goes out with the Page, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifob.</speaker>
	<l> Why don't you come, here's nobody. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Here I am. > /;' </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Jfib.</speaker>
	<l> Where } . .1: v </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Here. . [Gives her his Hand.</l>
	<l>I fab. My Lord, you may venture, Clarina will be</l>
	<l>Alone within this hour where you (hall entertain</l>
	<l>- v-.A'- Her</l>
	<l>v- (3®) _</l>
	<l>Heratycninr freedoms But yon mud day a whireiaicy</l>
	<l>Chamber till' my Lords abed-,,</l>
	<l>For none but I mud know of the favour (he defigns you </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Oh gods! what language do l here—</l>
	<l>Falfe and perfidious woman ,1 might have thought.</l>
	<l>Since thou wert gain’d foeafily by me,,</l>
	<l>Thou wouldft with equal hade yield to another. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>jfab.</speaker>
	<l> It isnot2L?r/7z; 3 whatfhall[ do> [she Jieals in.</l>
	<l>. Enter Lorenzo and Page. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A Pox of all Damn’d Cowardly fear.</l>
	<l>Now did I think I had drunk Nature up to refolution}</l>
	<l>I have heard of thole that could have dar’d in their drinks</l>
	<l>But I find, drunk or fober, ’tis all one in me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> The T ray tor’s here,</l>
	<l>Whom I will kill who e’rehe be.</l>
	<l>Lor f Boy, go fee for Ifabclla. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Boy.</speaker>
	<l> I fee a man fhould not be a Coward and a Lover</l>
	<l>At once— Isabella , Isabella , (he’s gone Sir. [Calls. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Yes villain, (he’s gone, and in her room</l>
	<l>Is one that willchadife thy boldness. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> That’s a proud word though, who e’re thou be 3</l>
	<l>But how I (hall avoid it-, is pad my underdanding. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Where art thou (lave ></l>
	<l>[Alberto gropes for him , he avoids him. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Tag.</speaker>
	<l> Take heart Sir, here’s company which I will</l>
	<l>Get to affid you— [Enter Antonio.</l>
	<l>Sir, as you are a Gentleman,affida drangerfet upon by Thieves.</l>
	<l>[They fight , Antonio with Alberto, [Xor. runs away</l>
	<l>Alberto falls is wounded. the while. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Who e’rethoube’d that takes the Tray tors part.</l>
	<l>Commend metothe wrong’d Antonio. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Alberto ! dear Alberto , is it thee ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio l</l>
	<l> . . «   . - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I am a(ham’d to (ay I am Antonio $</l>
	<l>Oh gods, why would youfuffer this midake } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Iam not wounded much.</l>
	<l>My greated pain is my concern for thee </l>
	<l>Friend thou art wrong’d, falfly and ba(ely wrong’d 3</l>
	<l>Clarina</l>
	<l>Clarina whom you lov'd and fear’d.</l>
	<l>Has now betray’d thy Honour with her own. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Without that fad addition to my grief,</l>
	<l>I (houldnot long have born the weight of life.</l>
	<l>Having deftroy’d thine by a dire miftake. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Thou art deceiv’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> Alas, why was it not permitted me</l>
	<l>Tolofe my Friend, or Wife, had one furviv’d,</l>
	<l>I might have dy’d in filencefor the other 3</l>
	<l>Oh my Alberto ! oh Clarina too— jVeeps. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Come, do not grieve for me, I (hall be well,</l>
	<l>I yet find ftrength enough to get a way 3</l>
	<l>And then I’le let thee know my fate and thine. [ Exeunt. /</l>
	<l>- SCENE. IV.</l>
	<l>Enter Clarina, Ifinena, and Kabella weeping.</l>
	<l>jfiib. For Heavens fake. Madam, pardon me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> Be dumb for ever faKe and treacherous woman.</l>
	<l>Was there no way but this to mask your Cheat }</l>
	<l>A Lye which has undone us all.</l>
	<l>jjab . Alas, ’twas in the dark, how could I know him }</l>
	<l>Pray forgive it me, and try my future fervice.</l>
	<l>Clar . I never will forgive thee naughty Girl 3</l>
	<l>Alberto now incens’d, will tell Antonio all. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> What need you care Madam .?</l>
	<l>Y ou are fecure enough.</l>
	<l>Clar . Thou falv’ft an error with a greater (till 3</l>
	<l>Doft thou not know Antonio's Jealoufie,</l>
	<l>Which yet is moderate, rais’d to a higher pitch,</l>
	<l>May ruine me, lfmena> and thy felf? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Sifter, there cannot be much harm in this,</l>
	<l>5 Tis an ill chance, ’tis true, for by it we have loft</l>
	<l>The pleafure of an innocent revenge</l>
	<l>Upon Antonio 3 but if underftood,</l>
	<l>We have but miss’d that end. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Ijmena ! %</l>
	<l>This 1</l>
	<l>A mfrfeaeewfMsfa dWsftiff afraudorp realim.</l>
	<l>/fib.- IVfacfnT, early in the morning</l>
	<l>fie to Alberto’s Lodgings', and tell him the miff a fee-</l>
	<l>Clar< ’Twilbetooia'te.,</l>
	<l>/fit. Si her, what think </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ctar.</speaker>
	<l> You fhould not be fo daring ,</l>
	<l>Befides, I blufhto think what ftrange opinion:</l>
	<l>He’Ie entertain of me the while.</l>
	<l>/fit . Do not let that affii6t you,</l>
	<l>Edtch my veil,,and if Antonio chance to ask for me.</l>
	<l>Tell him I’me' gone to Laura.</l>
	<l>Believe me, I will fet all ftrait again.</l>
	<l>Enter Isabella with the Veil. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> Thou haft more courage. Girl, then I.</l>
	<l>Ifnti What need is there of much of that.</l>
	<l>To encounter a gay young Lover,</l>
	<l>Where I amfure there cannot be much danger? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> Well take your chance, I wifh you luck Sir,</l>
	<l>For I am e’ne as much bent upon revenge.</l>
	<l>As thou art upon Marriage. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifit.</speaker>
	<l> Come, my-Veil, this and the night</l>
	<l>Will enough fecure mc</l>
	<l>[Puts on the Veit and goes out. £. Clar. and</l>
	<l>f .vl \</l>
	<l>you if I go my felf ?</l>
	<l>SCENE V.</l>
	<l>Difcovers Alberto and Afitonioo</l>
	<l>I V ' .  '  " </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Nay, thou fhalt fee’t before thou dpft revenge it,,</l>
	<l>In fuch a cafe, thy felf fhould be the witness.</l>
	<l>She knows not what has paft to night between us.</l>
	<l>Nor fhould fhe, if thou could’ft contain thy rage 3</l>
	<l>And that Antonioyou (hall promife me,</l>
	<l>To morrow place thy felf behind the Arras,</l>
	<l>And from thy eyes thy own misfortunes know</l>
	<l>What will not difobliged paffion do? j </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> He hide my anger in a feeming calm.</l>
	<l>C 33 )</l>
	<l>And what I'haveto do, confult the while, .</l>
	<l>And mask my vengeance underneath a fmile. Antonio,, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>rage.</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, there is without a Lady</l>
	<l>Defires to fpeak with you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Whois’t?</l>
	<l>Page . I know not, Sir, (he’s veild.</l>
	<l>Enter Ifmena weeding. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Conduct her in. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Albertoj Ifibella has undone us all! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> She weeps, and looks as innocent!</l>
	<l>— What mean you falfe diffembling Clarina ?</l>
	<l>What, have you borrow’d from deceit new Charms ?</l>
	<l>And think’ft: to fool me to a new belief. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm .</speaker>
	<l> How Sir, can you too be unkind ></l>
	<l>Nay then ’tistime to dye 3</l>
	<l>Alas, there wanted but your credit</l>
	<l>To this miftake, to make me truely miferable. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> What credit? what miftake > oh undeceive me.</l>
	<l>For I have done thee injuries paft forgiveness,</l>
	<l>If thou be’ffctruly innocent. - . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> ifabelU) under pretence of dpurting me</l>
	<l>For Lorenzo , on whom fhe has defigns to</l>
	<l>Make a Husband 3</l>
	<l>Has given him freedoms will undo my honour.</l>
	<l>If not prevented foon. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> May I credit this } and that it was not by thy</l>
	<l>Command fhe did it. \ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Be witness Heaven, my innocence in this,</l>
	<l>Which if you will believe, Fme fufe again. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I do believe thee, but thou art not fafe.</l>
	<l>Here, take this Poyniard, and revenge thy wrongs.</l>
	<l>Wrongs which I dare not beg a pardon for. [Hegives her </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> W hy. Sir, what have you done? have you a Dagger.</l>
	<l>Deceiv’d me, and do you not indeecove me ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Clarina ! do not ask that queftion,</l>
	<l>Too much of that has made me ruine thee 3</l>
	<l>It made me jealous,drunk with jealoufie.</l>
	<l>And then I did unravel all my fecrets.</l>
	<l>F ifm.</l>
	<l>( 34) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Whatfecrets, Sir? you have then feen Antonio. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Yes.</l>
	<l>Hah — Now Wit if ere thou didft poffess [_ 4 fdc.</l>
	<l>A Woman $ affift her at her need.</l>
	<l>.... Well Sir, rife and tell me, all j </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I will not rife till you have pardon’d me,</l>
	<l>Or punifht my misfortune. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Be what it will I do forgive it thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio Madam knows my happiness,</l>
	<l>For in my rage I told him that you lov’d me 5</l>
	<l>-—What (hall I do? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> I cannot blame you though it were unkind. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> This I could help, but I have promis’d him,</l>
	<l>That he (hall be a witness of this truth 5</l>
	<l>What fay you Madam do I not merit death ?</l>
	<l>Oh fpeak and let me know my doom what ere it be? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Make good your word. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> What mean you ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> What you have promis’d him, perform as you intended.,  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> What then? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Then come as you defign’d to vifit me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> But letmeknow what ’tis you mean to do,</l>
	<l>That ImayAft accordingly. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> No. Anfwer me to every queftion afk’d.</l>
	<l>And I perhaps may fet all ftraight again $</l>
	<l>’Tis now late, and I muft not be miffing.</l>
	<l>But if you love me, be no more Jealous of me. </l>
	<l>— Farewel. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Muft [ be Ignorant then of your defign f </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, Alberto.</l>
	<l>-And you (hall fee what Love will make a Woman do.</l>
	<l>f He leads hefwt. % </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Now am I caught again, inconftaht Nature.</l>
	<l>— Would (he had,lets of Beauty or of Wit,</l>
	<l>Or that Antonio did but lelsdeferve her 5</l>
	<l>— Or that the were not married.</l>
	<l>Or Vdeless Virtue, for ’tis that which aws me,</l>
	<l>That tender fenfe of nothing:</l>
	<l>And</l>
	<l>(3$)</l>
	<l>And makes the other Reafons feem as Bugbears,</l>
	<l>I Love Clarina more than he can do 5</l>
	<l>And yet this Virtue dothoppofe that Love,</l>
	<l>Tells me there lurks a treafon there</l>
	<l>Againft Antonios and Clarina s Virtue 5</l>
	<l>— ’Tis but too true indeed, and I’m not fafe,</l>
	<l>Whilft I conceal the Criminal within</l>
	<l>— I muft reveal it, for whilft I hide the Tray tor</l>
	<l>I feem to Love the Treafon to,</l>
	<l>— I will refign it then, fince ’tis less blame,</l>
	<l>To perifh by my pain, then live with fhame. [Exit. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ACT.</speaker>
	<l> III. SCENE. I.</l>
	<l>Enter Frederick and Laura. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> T Aura , Confider well my quality,</l>
	<l>I , And be not angry with your Fathers Confidence,</l>
	<l>Who left us here alone. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>tau.</speaker>
	<l> He will repent that Freedom when he knows.</l>
	<l>What ufe you’ve made on’t Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Fy, fy, Laura , a Lady bred at Court, and</l>
	<l>Yet want Complaifance enough to entertain</l>
	<l>A Gallant in private : this coy Humour</l>
	<l>Is not Ala-mode,</l>
	<l>—— Be not to peevifh with a heart that dyes for you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Pray tell me Sir, what is’t in me that can</l>
	<l>Encourage this;? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> That which is in all Lovely Women, Laura j</l>
	<l>A thoufand blufhes play about your Cheeks,</l>
	<l>Which (howsthe brifkness of the blood that warms them.</l>
	<l>If I but tell you how I do adore you.</l>
	<l>You ftraight decline your Eyes,</l>
	<l>Which does declare you underftand my meaning.</l>
	<l>And every fmile or frown betrays your thoughts,</l>
	<l>F 2</l>
	<l>And</l>
	<l>[Enter Maid.</l>
	<l>( i 6 )</l>
	<l>And yet you cry, you do not give me caufe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Maid.</speaker>
	<l> Curtins Madam waits without. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> I do not like his hafte.</l>
	<l>— Tell him he cannot be admitted now.</l>
	<l> \ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau .</speaker>
	<l> Sir, he is one that merits better treatment frqm you 5</l>
	<l>How can you injure thus the Man you Love?. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Madam alii your Eyes,</l>
	<l>Thofe powerful Attrads,</l>
	<l>And do not call their Forces fo in queftiom,</l>
	<l>As to believe they kindle feeble fires 5</l>
	<l>Such' as a Friendfhipcanfurmount. No Laura, . —</l>
	<l>They’ve done far greater miracles. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Sir ’tis in vain you tell me of their power,</l>
	<l>Unless they could have made a nobler Conquefr</l>
	<l>Then hearts that yield to every petty Vidor.</l>
	<l>— Look on me well.</l>
	<l>Can nothing here inform you of my Soul,</l>
	<l>And how it fcorns to treat on thefe conditions.</l>
	<l>[Looks on kins , he gazes with a half fmile, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Faith, no Laura.</l>
	<l>I fee nothing there but wondrous Beauty,</l>
	<l>And a deal of needless Pride, and fcorn 3</l>
	<l>And fuch as may be humbl’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Sir you miftake, that never can abate.</l>
	<l>But yet I know your power may do me injuries 3</l>
	<l>But I believe your guilty of no fin.</l>
	<l>Save your inconftancy which is fufficient3</l>
	<l>And Sir 1 beg I may not be the firft [Kneels and iveeps.</l>
	<l>May find new Crimes about you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Rife Laura thou haft but too many Beautyes,</l>
	<l>Which pray be careful that you keep conceal’d, [offers to go.</l>
	<l>Lan< 1 humbly thank you Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> —But whv fhould this interpofing Virtue check me.</l>
	<l>— Stay Laura tell me 3 niuft you marry Curtins ?</l>
	<l>La >/. Yes Si r, I muft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Laura you muft not, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> How Sir ! : </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> 1 fay you.fliall not marry him,</l>
	<l>Un’ess</l>
	<l>(37)</l>
	<l>Unless you offer up a victim, '7</l>
	<l>That may appeafe the anger you have rais'd in me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> lie offer up a 1000. prayers and tears. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> That will not do.</l>
	<l>Since thou’ft deny’d my juft-pretentions to thee.</l>
	<l>No less then what\L tould you off fhajl fatisfy me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Oh where is all your Honour, aud your Virtue ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Juft where it was, there’s no fuch real thing.</l>
	<l>I know that thou wertmadetobe poffeft,</l>
	<l>And he that does refufe it, loves thee leafh</l>
	<l>—There’s danger in my Love, and your delay.</l>
	<l>And you are moftfecure whilft you obey. [ Hejpulls her gently. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Then this fhall be my fafety, hold off</l>
	<l>draws a Dagger .</l>
	<l>Or IT forget you a ft my Prince. ; [He laughs . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Pretty Virago , how you raife my Love?</l>
	<l>— I have a Dagger too 5 What will you do )[shows her a Dagger.</l>
	<l>Enter Curtius.  ,</l>
	<l>v  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> How 1 the Prince ! arm’d againft Lanra too 1 [Draws. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Traytor, doft draw upon thy Prince ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Your Pardon Sir, I meant it on a Ravifher. [Bows.</l>
	<l>A foul mifguided Villain.</l>
	<l>One that fcarce merits the brave name of Man.</l>
	<l>One that betrays his friend, forfakes his Wife 5</l>
	<l>And would commit a Rape upon my Miftress. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Her prefence is thy fafety, be gone and leave me-. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> By no means Sir 5 the Villain may return ></l>
	<l>To which fair Laura fhould not be expos’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Slave darft thou difobey ? [offers to fight. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Hold Sir, and do not make me guilty of a (in,</l>
	<l>Greater then that Of yours. [Enter Salvator </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Salv.</speaker>
	<l> Gods pitty me $ here’s fine doings.— Why how</l>
	<l>Came this riftring Youngfter into my Houfe? Sir,</l>
	<l>Who fentr for you. Hah ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Love. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Salv.</speaker>
	<l> Love 3 with a witness to whom ? my Daughter ?</l>
	<l>— No Sir, (he’s otherwife difpos’d of I can allure </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>You.</speaker>
	<l> Begone gnd leave my Houfe and that quickly </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Toe.</speaker>
	<l> And thank me that I do not fecure</l>
	<l>Thee</l>
	<l>( 38 )</l>
	<l>Thee for a Tray tor, - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur .</speaker>
	<l> Will you not here me fpeak ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Salv.</speaker>
	<l> Not a word Sir, go begone, unlessyour</l>
	<l>Highness will have him apprehended. [JF0 Fred. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> No Sir, it fhall not need. — Curtins look</l>
	<l>Tq hear from me. — [Comes up to him and tells him fo in a me¬</l>
	<l>nacing tone , and go out fever ally. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Salv.</speaker>
	<l> Go Mrs. Minky, get you in. [Ex. Salv. and Laur.</l>
	<l>SCENE II.</l>
	<l>Enter Frederick pajfing in anger over the Stage 9</l>
	<l>meets Lorenzo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> O Sir, Fra glad I’ve found you , fpr</l>
	<l>I have the rareft news for you.</l>
	<l>Fred . What news? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Oh the Devil, he’s angry 5 —Why Sir the</l>
	<l>Pretty eft young — </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> There’s for your intelligence. [strides him and goes out , </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> So very well 5 How Mortal is the favour of</l>
	<l>Princes: thefe be turns of State now ? what the</l>
	<l>Devil ails he trow 5 fure ho could not be</l>
	<l>Offended with the news I have brought him , if he be he’s</l>
	<l>Strangely out of Tune 5</l>
	<l>And fure he has too much Wit to grow Virtuous at theic</l>
	<l>Years : No, no, he has had fomerepulfe from a</l>
	<l>Lady , and that’s a wonder 5 for he has a Tongue'and a</l>
	<l>Purfe that feldom fails 5 if youth and vigour would</l>
	<l>Stretch as far, he were the wonder of the Age. [Enter Curt. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Lorenzo , didft thou fee the Prince ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Marry did I, and feel him too.</l>
	<l>Curt  Why, did he ftrikeyou ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> I’m no true fubjeft if he did not 5 and that</l>
	<l>Only for doing that fervice which once was moft acceptable</l>
	<l>To him.— Prethee whats the matter with him,hah? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> I know not, leave me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Leave thee, what art thou out of humour too?</l>
	<l>Let</l>
	<l>( 39 )</l>
	<l>Let me but know who ’tis has difoblig’d thee, and lie — - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> What wilt thou ? ' r </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Never fee his face more if a Man. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> And what if a Woman ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l>' Then (he’s an Idle peevifh Slut I’le warrant her. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Conclude it fo and leave me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Nay now thou hall: faid the only thing that could.</l>
	<l>Keep me with thee, thou maift be defperateFie</l>
	<l>Tell you Curtins thefe Female mifchiess make men</l>
	<l>Take dangerous refolutions fometimes. [Enter Alber. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Curtins, Fve fomething to deliver to your Ear. [ivhifpzrs. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Any thing from Alberto is welcom. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Well I will be hang’d if there be not fome</l>
	<l>Mifchief in Agitation 5 it cannot be wenching 5</l>
	<l>They look all too dull and fober for that 5 and befides</l>
	<l>Then I fhould have been a party concern’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> The place and time. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> An hour hence i’th’ Grove by the River fide. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Alone thou fay ’ft ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Alone, the Prince will have it fo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> I will not fail a moment. [Fx. Alb.</l>
	<l>—So this ha’s eas’d my heart of half its load. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Flefneak away, for this is fome fighting</l>
	<l>Bufiness, and I may perhaps be invited a fecond,</l>
	<l>A Complement I care not for. [ offers to go. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Lorenzo, a word with you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tis fo, what (hall I do now ? [_ Afide. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Stay. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> I am a little in hafte my Lord. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Khali foon di(patch you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Ibeleive fo, for lam half dead already [Afide</l>
	<l>With fear , Sir, Ihave promis'd to make a vifit</l>
	<l>To a Lady, and— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> What Vve to fay (hall not detain you long. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> What a Dog was I, I went not,</l>
	<l>When he firft defir’d me to go ></l>
	<l>Oh impertinency, thou nrt.juftly rewarded 1 </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Lorenzo, may I believe you love me ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>( o c %</l>
	<l>4 °) ., .</l>
	<l>.  r </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> "N# what (hall I fay ,1 or no ?</l>
	<l>The Devil take me if I know. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Will you do me a favour ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> There ’tis again. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur .</speaker>
	<l> I know I may truft thee with a fecret. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Truly, Curtius I cannot tell 3</l>
	<l>In fome cafes I am not very retentive. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> I am going about a bufiness, that perhaps</l>
	<l>May take up all the time I have to live 3</l>
	<l>Anri I may never fee thy Sifter more 5</l>
	<l>Will you oblige me in a meftage to her ? . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> You know you may command me,</l>
	<l>—. Pme glad ’tis no wcfrfe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Come go with me into my Cabinet, 1</l>
	<l>And there ITe write to Lauras</l>
	<l>And prethee if thou hear’ft that I am dead 3</l>
	<l>Tell her I fell a Sacrifice to her 3 ' c j - </l>
	<l>And that’s enough 3 fheunderftands the reft: </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> But harky Curtin /, by your favour 3 this is but a</l>
	<l>Scurvy tale to carry to your Miftress j</l>
	<l>I hope you are not in earneft ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Yes. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Yes ? why 3 what a foolifh idle humoursthis in you ?</l>
	<l>I vow ’twill go near to break the poor Girls heart 5</l>
	<l>—Come be advis’d man. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Perhaps I may consider on’t for that reafon. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> There are few that go about fuch bufinefles,</l>
	<l>But have one thing or other to confider in favour of life,</l>
	<l>I find that even in themoft magnanimous:</l>
	<l>— Prethee who is’t with ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> That’s counfel 5 and pray let this too which I have</l>
	<l>Told you be a fecret, for ’twill concern your life. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> GoodCurtiuf take it back again then,</l>
	<l>Fora hundred to one but my over care of keeping it></l>
	<l>Will betray it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> Thouloveft thy felf better. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Well that’s a comfort yet   £ Exeunt.</l>
	<l>SCENE</l>
	<l>(4)</l>
	<l>' ' __  f f Jt v</l>
	<l>- ' « -  - 'l J . : .( .  f. ' «/ « , . ></l>
	<l>SCENE in. A Wood. j . ...</l>
	<l>Clor/is dref like a Country Boy follow'd by Gmlliam a Clowns</l>
	<l>Cloris comes reading a Letter,</l>
	<l>Clo, reads. Cloris beware of men 5 for though I my felf be one ,</l>
	<l>Tet I have the frailties of my Sex , and can diffemble too i</l>
	<l>Trujl none of us 0 for if thou doft , thou art undone j</l>
	<l>IVe make vows to all alike we fee.</l>
	<l>And even the befi of men , the Prince ,</l>
	<l>Is not to be credited in an affair of Love.</l>
	<l>—Oh Curtins , thy advice was very kind, '</l>
	<l>Had it arriv’d before I’de been undone!</l>
	<l>—Can Frederick. too be falfe ?</l>
	<l>A Prince, and be un juft to her that loves him too?</l>
	<l>—Surely it is impoflible—</l>
	<l>Perhaps thou lov’ft me too, and thisftnay be [ Pointing to the Letter .</l>
	<l>Some Plot of thine to try my conftancy:</l>
	<l>—How e’re it be, lince he could fail laft night</l>
	<l>Of feeing me, I have at lead a caufe to juftifie</l>
	<l>This fhameful change 5 and fure in this difguife, \_L00ky on</l>
	<l>I (hall not foon be known, doft think Khali } her felf </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Why forfooth, what do you intend to pass for,</l>
	<l>A Maid or a Boy ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Why, what I feem to be, will it not do ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, yes, it may do, but I know not what 5</l>
	<l>I wo’d Love would Tranfmogriphy me to a Maid now,</l>
	<l>—:We houid be the prettieft couple 5</l>
	<l>Don’t you remember when you dreft me up the laft</l>
	<l>Carnival, was not I the woundieft handfom lals</l>
	<l>A body could fee in a Summers day ></l>
	<l>There was Claud the Shepherd as frekifti after me</l>
	<l>I'le warrant you, and (imper’d andtriptit like anything. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> I, but they fay ’tis dangerous for young</l>
	<l>Maids to live at Court. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> N ay, then I houid be loth to give temptation.</l>
	<l>—Pray forfooth, what’s that you read fo often there ?</l>
	<l>.Vi\ U G Clor</l>
	<l>C 4) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>dor.</speaker>
	<l> An advice to young Maids that are in Love. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> I, I, that fame Love is a very vengeance thing</l>
	<l>jvo’d I were in Love too 5 I fee it makes a body Valiant 5</l>
	<l>One neither feels hunger nor cold that is polled with it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l>' Thou art i’th’right, it can do miracles.</l>
	<l>Guil . So it feems, for without a miracle you and T could never</l>
	<l>Have rambled aboutthefe Woods all night without either</l>
	<l>Bottle or Wallet: I could e’ne cry for hunger now. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> What a dull Soul this fellow hath }</l>
	<l>Sure it can never feel the generous pains</l>
	<l>Of Love, as mine does now 5 Oh how I glory</l>
	<l>To find my heart above the common rate 3</l>
	<l>Were not my Prince incondant!</l>
	<l>I would not envy what the bleded do above :</l>
	<l>But he is falfe good Heaven ! — weeps. [Guil. howl.</l>
	<l>What dod thou feel that thoufhouldd weep with me > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Nothing but hunger, (harp hunger forfooth. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Leave calling me forfooth it will betray us. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> What (hall I call youthen > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Call me Philibert , or any thing.</l>
	<l>And be familiar with me:putonthy Hat lead any come and (ee us.</l>
	<l>Guil . ’Tis a hard name but I'le learn it by heart.</l>
	<l>— Well Philibert — what (hall we do when we come to Court</l>
	<l>[ Puts on his Hat,</l>
	<l>Befides eating and drinking, which I fhall do in abundance. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> We mud get each of us a fervice.</l>
	<l>But thou art fuch a Clown. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Nay fay not fo honed Phillibert : for look yee,</l>
	<l>I am much the properer fellow of the two. Walks </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Well try thy fortune} but be fure you never difeover</l>
	<l>Me, what ever quedions may chance to be afked thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> I warrant the honed Lad, I am true and trudy 3</l>
	<l>But I mud be very familiar with you you (ay. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Yes before Company.</l>
	<l>Guil . Pray let me begin and Pratdice a little now</l>
	<l>A’nt pleafe you, for fear I (hould not be fawey enough,</l>
	<l>When we arrive at Court. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Fie warrant you you’l foon learn thete,</l>
	<l>Quil</l>
	<l>C43)</l>
	<l>Guil . —Oh Lord vhillibert! vhillibcrt / I fee a Man a coming</l>
	<l>Moft deadly fine, lets run away.</l>
	<l>Clor . Thus thou haft ferv’d me all this night.</l>
	<l>There's not abu(h we come at but thou ftartftthus. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tis true you are a lover and may flay the danger on't.</l>
	<l>But Fie make fare for one. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>dor .</speaker>
	<l> It is the Prince, Oh Gods what makes he here!</l>
	<l>With looks diforder’dtoos this place is fit for Death and fad</l>
	<l>Defparr j the melancholy Spring a fleepy murmure makes,</l>
	<l>A proper Confort for departing Souls, \</l>
	<l>When mixt with dying Grones, and the thick boughs</l>
	<l>Compofe a difmal roof3</l>
	<l>Dark as the gloomy fhades of Death or Graves .</l>
	<l>—He comes this way lie hide my felf a while. [Goes behind m</l>
	<l>Enter Frederick. Bufi. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> But yet not this nor my difpight to Laura,</l>
	<l>Shall make me out of Love with life,</l>
	<l>Whilffc I have youthful fires about my heart:</l>
	<l>—Yet I muft fight with Curtins,</l>
	<l>And fb chaftife the Pride of that fond Maid,</l>
	<l>Whofe faucy Virtue durft controul my flame 3</l>
	<l>—And yet I love her not as I do doris 3</l>
	<l>But fain I would have overcome that Chaftity</l>
	<l>Of which the foolifh Beauty boafts fo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Curtins I thank thee, now I do believe thee.</l>
	<l>[The Prince realms.</l>
	<l>Guilliam. if thou feefi: any fighting anon.</l>
	<l>Be fare you run out and call fame body. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> You need not bid me run away when I once</l>
	<l>See them go to that.</l>
	<l>Enter Curtius. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Sir I am come as you commanded me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> When you confider what you've lately done.</l>
	<l>You will not wonder why I fent for you 3</l>
	<l>And when I mean to fight, I do not ufe to parly 3</l>
	<l>Come draw. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Show me my Enemy, and then if lam flow —</l>
	<l>jF red. I am he, needft thou one more powerful }</l>
	<l>G 2 </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>(44)</l>
	<l>Curt, You Sir, what have I done to make you fo? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> If yet thou wanted a further proof of it,</l>
	<l>Know lie difpute my Claim to Laura. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> That mud not be with me Sir,</l>
	<l>God forbid that I (hould raife my Armagainft my Prince:</l>
	<l>—-If Laura have fo little Faith and Virtue,</l>
	<l>To render up that right belongs to me.</l>
	<l>With all my heart I yield her</l>
	<l>To any but to you 5</l>
	<l>And Sir for your own fake you mud not have her. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> YourReafon? . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Sir you’re already marryed.</l>
	<l>Fred . Thou lyed, and feek’d excufes for thy Cowardice.</l>
	<l>Curt, i with you would recall that hady injury,</l>
	<l>Yet this He bear from you, who know ’tis falfe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Will nothing move thee? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> You would believe fo Sir if I (hould tell you</l>
	<l>That befides all this,. I have a juder caufe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Juder then that of Laura ? call it up then.</l>
	<l>And let it fave thee from a further (hame.</l>
	<l>Curt . Yes fo I will ’tis that of Cloris ,</l>
	<l>Who needs my aids much more \</l>
	<l>Do you remember fuch a Virgin Sir?</l>
	<l>For fo (he was till (he knew Frederick J</l>
	<l>The fweeted innocent that ever Nature made. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Not thy own Honour, nor thy Love to Laura</l>
	<l>Would make the draw, and now at Cloris name.</l>
	<l>Thou art incens’d, thy eyes all red with rage:</l>
	<l>— Oh thou had rows’d my Soul ,</l>
	<l>Nor would ! judify my wrongs to her,</l>
	<l>Unless it were to fatisfy my jealoufie.</l>
	<l>Which thou had rais’d in me by this concern.</l>
	<l>-—Draw or. I’le kill thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Stay Sir, and. hear me out. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> I will not day, now I refied on all thy</l>
	<l>Former kindned to her — </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> I will not fight, butI’ldefend my. felf. [rhej fight.</l>
	<l>Fred . We are betray’d.</l>
	<l>(45> </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Yes Sir, and you are wounded, ' .0 I </l>
	<l>[Guil. runs bawling out> they ah both wounded. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Heaven defend the Prince. \_she peeps. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> I hear fome coming, go be gone,</l>
	<l>And lave thy felf by flight. [Fred, ftands leaning on his sword. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Sir give me leave to ftay,my flight will look like guilt </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> By no means Curtins , thou wiltbe taken here,</l>
	<l>And thou (halt never charge me with that Crime of betraying</l>
	<l>Thee : when we meet next wee’l end it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> I muft obey you then. [ Exit Curt.</l>
	<l>Enter Cloris. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, has the Villain hurt you ? [ she fupports him .</l>
	<l>—Pray Heaven my forrows do not betray me now.</l>
	<l>For fince he’s falfe, I fain would dy conceal’d. [Aftde.</l>
	<l>— Show me your wound and I will ty it up.</l>
	<l>Alas you bleed extreamly — </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Kind youth thy luceours are in vain though welcom.</l>
	<l>For though I bleed I am not wounded much. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> No? Why did you let him pals unpunifht then,</l>
	<l>Who would have hurt you more?</l>
	<l>Enter Guillam with a Galliard. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Serv.</speaker>
	<l> Where was’t ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Look ye Sir there, don’t you feethem. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Serv.</speaker>
	<l> How does your Highness ? this fellow told me</l>
	<l>Of a quarrel here, which made me haft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Be filent, and carry me to my own apartment. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Serv.</speaker>
	<l> Alas Sir, is it you that fought? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> No more queftions. —.</l>
	<l>Kind Boy pray leave me not till I have found;</l>
	<l>A way to recompencethy pretty care of me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> I will wait on you Sir. [ Exeunt all but Guillam.</l>
	<l>Enter Lorenzo. [ Veeps firfi. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> What’s the matter here ? the Prince is wounded too.</l>
	<l>Oh what a Dog was I to know of fome fuch thing,</l>
	<l>And not fecure them all ?</l>
	<l>Lorenzo ftands g iving at Gill. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> ftands tabering his Hat and fcruing his face .</l>
	<l>—What’s here ? Hah, hah, hah, this is the pleafanteft</l>
	<l>- - Fellow</l>
	<l>(40</l>
	<l>Fellow that ere I faw in niy life.</l>
	<l>Prethee Friend what’s thy Name£</l>
	<l>. Guil. My Name., an’t (hall like yee</l>
	<l>My Name is, is Guillam. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> From whence comeft thoii? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> From a Village a great huge way off. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> And wbat’s thybufiness here, hah? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Truly Sir, not to tell a ly,</l>
	<l>1 come to get a fervice here at Court. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A fervice at Court j hah, hah, that’s a pleafant</l>
	<l>Humour y’faith. Why fellow what canftthou do ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Do Sir, I can do any thing. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Why what canftthou do? canft thou dresswell?</l>
	<l>—Set a Perruke to advantage, ty a Crevatt,</l>
	<l>And Cufss, put on a Belt with dexterity, hah ?</l>
	<l>Thefe be the parts that muft recommend you# </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> I know not what you mean,</l>
	<l>But I am fure I can do them all. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Thou art confident it feems, and I can tell</l>
	<l>You Sirrah, that’s a great ftep to preferment 5</l>
	<l>— But well go on then, canft ride the great Horfe ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Thebigeft in all our Town</l>
	<l>I have rid a thoufand times.</l>
	<l>Lor, That’s wells canft Fenced </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Fence Sir, what’s that? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A term we ufe for the Art and (kill of handling a Weapo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> I can thrafti Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> What’s that Man ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Why Sir it is it is — thrafhing. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> An Artift I vow 5 canft play on any Mufick ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Oh moft rogically Sir, I have a Bagpipe that</l>
	<l>Every breath fets the whole Village a Dancing. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Better ftill > and thou canft Dance lie warrant? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Dance, he, he, he, I vow you’ve light on</l>
	<l>My Mafter piece y’fegs. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> And He try thee. Boy go fetch fomeof tbe[Y? the Page.</l>
	<l>Mufick hither which I keep in pay ? [Exit Boy.</l>
	<l>— But hark you Friend, thong I love Dancing very well.</l>
	<l>And</l>
	<l>And that may recommend thee in a great degree 5</l>
	<l>Yet tis wholy neceflary that you (hould be valiant too ></l>
	<l>We graet ones ought to be ferv’d by men of valour.</l>
	<l>For we are very liable to be affronted by many here</l>
	<l>To our faces, which we would gladly have beaten behind</l>
	<l>Our backs 5 — But Pox on’t thou haft not the Huf£</l>
	<l>And Grimass of a Man of Prowess. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Gail.</speaker>
	<l> As for fighting though I do not care for it.</l>
	<l>Yet I can do’t if any body angers me or fo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> But I muft have you learn to do’t when</l>
	<l>Any body angers me too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Sir,they toldmelftiould have no need on’t</l>
	<l>Here , but I (hall learn.</l>
	<l>Lor, Why you Fool that’s not a thing to be learn’d,</l>
	<l>—- That’s a brave inclination born with Man,</l>
	<l>A brave undaunted fomething, a thing that.</l>
	<l>That, comes from, from 5 I know not what.</l>
	<l>For I was born without it.</l>
	<l>Enter Pag: and Mafic k.</l>
	<l>Oh are you come > lets fee Sirrah your Activity,</l>
	<l>For I muft tell you that’s another ftep to preferment.</l>
	<l>[He dances a j fzgg en Paifant.</l>
	<l>Tis well perform’d, well hadft thou but wit.</l>
	<l>Valour, BonMeen , good garb, a perruke.</l>
	<l>Conduct and (ecrefie in Love Affairs, and half</l>
	<l>A dozen more good qualities, thou wert</l>
	<l>Fit for fomething $ but I will try thee.</l>
	<l>Boy, let him have better Cloaths,asfor his Documents</l>
	<l>lie give him thofe my felf.</l>
	<l>Guil, Hah, I don’t like that word, it founds terribly. [ Afide .</l>
	<l>[Exit, Page and Guil. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> This fellow may be of u(e to me 5 being</l>
	<l>Doubtless very honeft becaufe he is lo very fimple 5</l>
	<l>For to fay truth we men of parts are fometimes</l>
	<l>Over-wife, witness my laft nights retreat</l>
	<l>From but a fuppofed danger, and returning to fall</l>
	<l>Into a real one. Well lie now to lfabella y</l>
	<l>And know her final refolutian j if CUrina will</l>
	<l>Be</l>
	<l>4</l>
	<l>( 48 )</l>
	<l>Be kind, fo 3 if not, there be thof£ that will.</l>
	<l>— And though I cannot any Conqueft boaft,</l>
	<l>For all the'time and money I have loft.</l>
	<l>At leaft on Ifabel lie be revenged.</l>
	<l>And have the flattering baggage foundly Twinged,</l>
	<l>And rather then (he (hall efcape my Anger,</l>
	<l>My felf wilL be the Hero that (ball bang her. [Exit. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ACT.</speaker>
	<l> IV. SCENE. I.</l>
	<l>Enter Ifmena and Ifabel.</l>
	<l>r 1 \  i'i i t ' 1 ‘ ‘ 1  f 1 l \</l>
	<l>dam turn y° ur back to that fide,</l>
	<l>[VJl. Tor there Antonio is hid 5 he muft not fee your</l>
	<l>Face: now raife your voice that he may hear what ’tis you lay. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> II warrant you. Ifibella ,</l>
	<l>was ever wretched Womans fate like mine, ; . . r n</l>
	<l>Forc’d to obey the rigid Laws of Parents,</l>
	<l>And marry with a Man I did not Love ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Ohtheres my caufe of fear. £Ant. peeps. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Though fince I had him thou knowft I have indeavour’d</l>
	<l>To make his will my Law3</l>
	<l>Till by degrees and Cuftom, which makes things natural,</l>
	<l>I found this heart, which ne’re had been ingag’d</l>
	<l>To any qther, grow more foft to him 5</l>
	<l>And (till the more he lov’d, the more I was oblig’d.</l>
	<l>And made returns (till kinder 3 till I became o — </l>
	<l>Not only to allow, but to repay his tendernefi. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifa.</speaker>
	<l> She Counterfeits rarely. [A/trfe.</l>
	<l>Madam indeed I have obferv’d this truth.</l>
	<l> , (   t j ; . . j . .. . .  j </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> See who ’tis knocks. [One knockj . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> What wll this come to? [Aftde. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifi.</speaker>
	<l> Madam 'tis Alberto.</l>
	<l>- Enter Alberto. [Born. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, yQ’ye often told me that you Lov’d me,</l>
	<l>.Which I with Womens' ufiial Pride believ’d 5</l>
	<l>w. 9</l>
	<l>And</l>
	<l>( 49 )</l>
	<l>And now encourag’d by my hopeful promifes.</l>
	<l>You look for fome returns 3 Sir 3 is it fo ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> What means (he ?</l>
	<l>Pray Heaven I anfwer right 3 Afide. : </l>
	<l>— —Madam, if I have err’d in that belief, tji], >7 vr :>.—</l>
	<l>To know I dofo, is fufficient punilhment. , ; ' r'</l>
	<l>—Lovers, Madam, though they have no returns,</l>
	<l>Like finking men, ftill catch at all they meet with 3</l>
	<l>And whilftthey live, though in themid’ft offtorms,</l>
	<l>Becaufe they v/ifh, they alfo hope for calms. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> And did youSir, confider whol was? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Yes, Madam, Wife unto my Friend Antonio ..,</l>
	<l>The only man that has an intereft here:</l>
	<l>—But, Madam, that mud ftill fubmit to Love. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm .</speaker>
	<l> Canft thou at once be true to him and me? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Madam, I know not that,</l>
	<l>But fince I raufl loofe one.</l>
	<l>My Friendfhip I can better lay afide. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Haft thou forgot how dear thou art to him ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> No, I do believe lam, and that his life</l>
	<l>Were but a worthless trifle, if I needed it 3 #</l>
	<l>Yet, Madam, you are dearer to him ftill.</l>
	<l>Then his Alberto 3 and ’tis fo with me: Vf</l>
	<l>—Him I efteem, but you I do adore 3</l>
	<l>And he whofeSoul’s incenfibleoflove.</l>
	<l>Can never grateful to his Friendfhip prove. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> By your example. Sir, I’le ftill retain.</l>
	<l>My love for him 3 and what I had for you,</l>
	<l>Which was but Friendfhip, Lie abandon too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Happy Antonio.— [ [Ajtde . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Pray what have you Antonio cannot own ?</l>
	<l>Has he not equal beauty, if not, exceeding thine ?</l>
	<l>Has he not equal vigour, wit, and valour ?</l>
	<l>And all that even raifes Men to Gods,</l>
	<l>Wer’t not for poor Mortality ?</l>
	<l>_Vain man, could’ftthou believe</l>
	<l>That 1 would quit my duty to this Husband,</l>
	<l>And facrifice his right to thee?</l>
	<l>H -Could’ft</l>
	<l>—Could’ft thou believe me yefterday .?</l>
	<l>When from thy importunity and impudence,</l>
	<l>To fend thee from me 5</l>
	<l>I promis’d thee to love thee 5</l>
	<l>—Nay rather. Treacherous man,</l>
	<l>Could’ft thou believe I did not hate thee then,</l>
	<l>Whobafely would betray thy friend and me ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Sure this is earnefr. A fide </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Oh brave Clarina 1 A fide.. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Speak Traytor to my Fame and Honour 5</l>
	<l>Was there no woman, but Antonios. Wife,</l>
	<l>With whom thou could’ft commit fo foul a crime ?</l>
	<l>And none but he, too bring to publick fhame ?</l>
	<l>A man whotrufted thee, and lov’d thee too?</l>
	<l>—Speak-—and if yet thou haft a fenfe of Vertue,</l>
	<l>Call to the Saints for pardon, or thou dy’ft.</l>
	<l>[S/6e draws-a Poniard , and runs at hitn hejieps</l>
	<l>back1 to avoid it . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Hold Clarina ! —I am amaz’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> But ftay,</l>
	<l>Thou fay’ft my Beauty forc’d thee to this wickedness</l>
	<l>And that’s the caufe you have abus’d Antonio 5</l>
	<l>—Nor is it all the power I have with him,</l>
	<l>Can make him credit what I tell him of thee $</l>
	<l>And fhould I live, I ftill muft be purfu’d by thee.</l>
	<l>And unbeliev’d by him:</l>
	<l>— Alberto , thou (halt ne’re be guilty more,</l>
	<l>Whilft this—and this may meet.</l>
	<l>£ Offering to wound her felf is fta/d by Alb. and Ifab. they</l>
	<l>-  Jet \fm.in a Chair  Alb kneels weeding. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Hold mylTivinec/rfr/.'— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Shall I difcover my felf, or fteal away ? [ ’Afide ..</l>
	<l>And all aftiam’d of life after this Action 5</l>
	<l>Go where the Sun or day may ever find me :</l>
	<l>Oh what Vertue I’ve abus’d— r.</l>
	<l>Curfe on my little Faith 5</l>
	<l>And all the Curfes madpess can invent.</l>
	<l>Light on my groundless jcaloufie. Fir. Antonio. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>C$0 </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Marina, why focruel to my heart?</l>
	<l>’Tis true, I love you, butwitti cliafte an ardour, </l>
	<l>As Souls departing pay theJDities v .. j</l>
	<l>When with inceflant fighs they,hafte a way, ’</l>
	<l>And leave humanity behind 5 oh! £0 did I</l>
	<l>Abandon all the lefTer joy- oflife, . r r , , r 7</l>
	<l>For that of being permitted but t’adoreyey</l>
	<l>Alas, if’twere difpleaflngto you,</l>
	<l>Why did your felf encourage it ?</l>
	<l>I might have languifh’das I did before,</l>
	<l>And hid thofe crimes which make you hate me now:</l>
	<l>—Oh I am loft ] Antonio, thouft undone me 5 [ He rifes in rage.</l>
	<l>—Here me ungrate 3 I fwear by all that’s good,</l>
	<l>I’le wafh away my mifchief with thy blood. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifib.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio hears you not Sir, for he’s departed. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifn .</speaker>
	<l> Is Antonio gone ?</l>
	<l>[_$he looks pcartly up,who before lay half dead </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> How’s this, has fhe but feign’d ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifni.</speaker>
	<l> No, it was but feign’d 5 1 hope this proof 1J -</l>
	<l>Of what I’ve promis’d you, does not difpleafe you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Ami thus fortunate,thusftrangelyhappy ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifn.</speaker>
	<l> Time will confirm it to you—go, do not</l>
	<l>Now thank mefor’c, butfeek Antonio out.</l>
	<l>Perhaps, he may have too great a fence of the h ' ' ; 1</l>
	<l>Mifchiess his jealoufleshad like to have caus’d $</l>
	<l>But conjure him to take no notice of what’s paft tome j</l>
	<l>This eafie flight of mine fecures our fears.</l>
	<l>And ferves to make Antonio confident: , / ‘; ..</l>
	<l>Who now will unbelieve his eyes and ears?</l>
	<l>And fince before, when I was innocent.</l>
	<l>He could fufpeft my love and duty too 5</l>
	<l>I’letry w T hatmy difTemblingitwill do :</l>
	<l>—Gohafte. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Madam, I go furpriz’d with love and wonder. [F.Alb. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifn.</speaker>
	<l> You’l be more furpriz’d, when you know ' [_Aide.</l>
	<l>That you are cheated too as well as Antonio. \f xcnrit.</l>
	<l>- ASJOiilZ-T.</l>
	<l>U2</l>
	<l>SCENE IL</l>
	<l>Enter Curtius dijguisd in a 'Black, Ter Tuque and Beard \ with</l>
	<l>Pietro dijguifed alfo.</l>
	<l>Curt . Well, what haft thou learn’d> </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> News enough Sir, but none good 5</l>
	<l>That the Princes wounds are fmall.</l>
	<l>So that he intends to take the Air this evening 5</l>
	<l>That he folicites Laura hard 5</l>
	<l>And, Sir, that you are proclaim’d Tray tor. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> So, what fays the Meflenger youfent to Claris? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, he brings fad tydings back. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Whattydmgs? is (hedead</l>
	<l>That would revive my Soul,</l>
	<l>And fortifie my eafie nature with fame wicked notions.</l>
	<l>As deep as thofe this flattering Prince made ufeo£</l>
	<l>When he betray’d my Sifter 5 Prety cloris:</l>
	<l>—Come, fpeak it boldly, for nothing elfe</l>
	<l>Will make me do her juftice. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Tiet.</speaker>
	<l> No Sir, (he is not dead.</l>
	<l>But fled, and none knows whether 5</l>
	<l>Only Guilliam attends her.</l>
	<l>Curt Worfe and worfej but what of Laura }' </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> She, Sir, is kept a Prifoner by her Father.</l>
	<l>And l'peaks with none but thofe that come from Frederick  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Laura confin’d tops Vis timeto.haften then,</l>
	<l>With my, till now,,almoft difarm’d revenge :</l>
	<l>—Thus I may pals unknown the ftrcetsof Florence ,</l>
	<l>And find an opportunity to reach this Princes heart</l>
	<l>—Oh vengeance ! luxurious vengeance.</l>
	<l>Thy Pleafuresturna Rival to my love.</l>
	<l>And make the mightier Conqueft o’re my heart.   :</l>
	<l>—Cloris—l will revenge thy tears and- lufleringsy</l>
	<l>And to fecure the doom of him that wrong’d thee,</l>
	<l>I’le call on injur’d Laura too.</l>
	<l>Ffere take thefe Pictures— and where thou fee’ft</l>
	<l>\pives him Boxes,</l>
	<l>A</l>
	<l>( 53 )</l>
	<l>A knot of Gallants, open one or two, as if by ftealth.</l>
	<l>To gaze upon the Beauties, and then ftraightclofe them—-</l>
	<l>But day, here comes the only man</l>
	<l>I could have wifh’d for, he’le proclaim my bufiness</l>
	<l>Better then a Picture ora Trumpet. They Jlandby,</l>
	<l>QCurtius takes bachtheVitfures.</l>
	<l>Enter Lorenzo and Guii'Iiam drefi in fineifi Cloaths , but</l>
	<l>the fame high-crorvn d Hat, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Did, ha, ha, ha, did ha, ha, $ did ever any</l>
	<l>Mortal man behold fuch a Figure as thou art now ?</l>
	<l>Well, I fee ’tis a damnable thing not to</l>
	<l>Be born a Gentleman 5 the Devil himfelf</l>
	<l>Can never make thee truly jantee now:</l>
	<l>—Come, come, come forward 5 thefe Cloaths become</l>
	<l>Thee, as a Saddle does a Sow 5 why corn’d: thou not?</l>
	<l>—Why— ha, ha, I hope thou halt not [_He advances formerly</l>
	<l>Hanfeird thy new Breeches, looking .</l>
	<l>Thou look’dfo filth ly on’t.</l>
	<l>Gill . No, Sir, I hope, I have more manners then fo 5</l>
	<l>But if I fhould, ’tis not my fault y</l>
	<l>For the necedary houfesnre hard „</l>
	<l>To be met withal here at Court. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Very well Sirrah i you begin already to be</l>
	<l>Witty with the Court 5 but lean tell you, it has as</l>
	<l>Many neceflary places in’t, as any Court inChriftendom—,</l>
	<l>But what a Hat thou had? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Gill.</speaker>
	<l> Why Sir, though I fay’t, this is accounted of</l>
	<l>In our Village 5 but l had another but now,</l>
	<l>Which blew off in a high wind 5 and I never mid it.</l>
	<l>Till I had an occafion to pluck it offto a young</l>
	<l>Squire, they call a Lacque 5 and Fegs</l>
	<l>I had none at all 5 and becaufe I would notlofe</l>
	<l>My Leg for want of a Hat, I fetch’d this- 5 </l>
	<l>Andl can tell you, Sir, it has afafhionable brim. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> A fools head of your own, has it not 5</l>
	<l>The,boys will hoot atusas wepaft—hah, ' .</l>
	<l>( 54 )</l>
	<l>Who be thefe, who be thefe— \Gm towards Curt.</l>
	<l>Curt . Here— this to Don Alonjb— this to the and Piet.</l>
	<l>Englifh County and this you may (how to the</l>
	<l>Young German Prince—and this— [ Gives Piet. Titfnres,</l>
	<l>I will referve for higher Prices. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> Will you (how none to the Courtiers, Sir } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Away you fool, I deal innofuch trafh. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> How Sir, how was that ? pray how came we to</l>
	<l>Gain your dif-favour? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> I cry you mercy Sir, pray what are you ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A Courtier,Sir, leanaflureyou.</l>
	<l>And one of the bed rank too 5</l>
	<l>I have the Princes ear. Sir—</l>
	<l>—What have you there—hah— Pictures, let me fee—</l>
	<l>What, are they to be bought ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, they are Copies of mod fair Originals,</l>
	<l>Not to be bought, but hired. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Say you fo Friend 5 the price, the price. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Five thoufand Crowns a month. Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> The price is fomewhat faucy. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, they be curious Pieces, were never blown upon,</l>
	<l>Have never been in Courts, nor hardly Cities. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Upon my word that’s confiderable 3</l>
	<l>Friend, pray where do you live } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> In the Piazzo , near the Palace. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Well, put up your ware, fhow not a face of them</l>
	<l>Till I return , fori will bring you</l>
	<l>The bed Chapman in all Florence ,</l>
	<l>Except the Duke himfelf. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> You mud be fpeedy then.</l>
	<l>Fori to morrow (hall be going towar dsRome. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A fubtle Rafcal this, thou think’d, I warrant.</l>
	<l>To make a better Market amongd the Cardinals 5</l>
	<l>—But take my word, ne’rea Cardinal of them all</l>
	<l>Comes near this man, I mean, to bring you in</l>
	<l>Matters of Beauty— fo, this will infalliably make [fifide.</l>
	<l>My peace again 5 look ye friend-- </l>
	<l>Be ready, for ’tis the Prince, the.noble generous Fndenc</l>
	<l>cuV' That</l>
	<l>(K)</l>
	<l>That I defign your Merchant. [Goes out.</l>
	<l>Curt . Your Servant Sir—- that is Guiltiam></l>
	<l>I cannot be miftaken in him;, go call him back,</l>
	<l>QPietro fetches hint back z who puts on a furly Face,</l>
	<l>r-Friend what art thou ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> What am I, why what am I j do’ft thou not fee</l>
	<l>What I am 5 a Courtier Friend.</l>
	<l>Curt . But what’s thy name?</l>
	<l>Guil, My name, I have notyetconfider’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> What was thy name ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> What was my name? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Yes friend, thou had’ft one. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Yes friend thou had’ft one. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Dog, do’ft ecchome? do’ft thou repeat 5 [shakes hint,</l>
	<l>I fay again, what is thy name? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Oh horrible— why. Sir, it was Guilliam</l>
	<l>W hen I was a filly Swain. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Guilliam — the fame j</l>
	<l>Did ft thou not know a Maid whofe name was Claris ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, there was fuch a Maid,</l>
	<l>Butnowfhe’s none. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Was fuch a Maid 5 but now fhe i s none:</l>
	<l>—The lave upbraids my griess. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, Sir, fo I faid. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cur.</speaker>
	<l> So you faid. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Why, yes Sir, what do you repeat? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> What mean you Sirrah? have you a mind to</l>
	<l>Have your Throat cut? tell me where fheis. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> I dare as well be hang’d 5</l>
	<l>Now muft Idevifealie, or never look Cloris</l>
	<l>In the face more.</l>
	<l>Curt . Here’s Gold for thee 5 I will befecret too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Oh, Sir, the poor Maid you fpeak of is dead ! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Dead ! where dy’d fhe ? and how ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Now am I put to my wits 5 this ’tis to begin</l>
	<l>In fin, as our Curate faid 5 I muft go on:</l>
	<l>—Why Sir, fhe came into the Wood, —and hard by a</l>
	<l>River fide—fhe figh’d, and fhe wept full fore 5</l>
	<l>And</l>
	<l>[Afide.</l>
	<l>[A fide.</l>
	<l>[Ajide.</l>
	<l>(50 .... .</l>
	<l>And cryd two or three times out upon Curtins ,</l>
	<l>--And-then- [Howls,. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Poor c!ork , thy fate was too fevere.</l>
	<l>Grlil. And then as! was faying, Sir,</l>
	<l>She leapt into the River, and fwam up the Stream. [Curt, weeps, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Viet.</speaker>
	<l> And why up the Stream friends</l>
	<l>Gutl, Becaufe (he was a Woman— and that’s all. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Farewel, and thank thee. [Eat. Guil.</l>
	<l>—Poor Clork dead, and banifh’d too from Laura 5</l>
	<l>Was ever wretched Lovers te like mine !</l>
	<l>—And he who injures me, has power to do fo $</l>
	<l>—But why, where lies this power about this man ?</l>
	<l>Is it his charms of Beauty, or of Wit ></l>
	<l>Or that great name he has acquir’d in War ?</l>
	<l>Is it the Majefty, that Holy fomethmg,</l>
	<l>That guards the perfon of this Demi-god ?</l>
	<l>This aws not me, there mull: be fomething more.</l>
	<l>Forever when I call upon my wrongs 5</l>
	<l>Something within me pleads To kindly for him.</l>
	<l>As would perfwademe that he could not erre.</l>
	<l>—Ah, what is this? where lies this power divine.</l>
	<l>That can fo eafily make a (lave of mine ? [ Exeunt .</l>
	<l>SCENE. III. </l>
	<l>></l>
	<l>Enter Frederick and Cloris finely drefi, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tismuchmethinks, a Boy offo dejectcd.</l>
	<l>Humble birth, fhould have fo much of fenfe.</l>
	<l>And foul about him. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>clor.</speaker>
	<l> I know notthat 5 but if I have a thought</l>
	<l>Above that humble Birth or Education,</l>
	<l>It was infpir’dby Love. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Still you raifemy wonder greater 5</l>
	<l>—Thou a Lo ver ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, my Lord, though I am young.</l>
	<l>I've felt the power of Beauty 5</l>
	<l>And fhould you look upohthe objeft. Sir, J</l>
	<l>Your</l>
	<l>( 57 ) .</l>
	<l>Your wonders (bon wouldceafe, ; )ft ':\0</l>
	<l>Each look does even Animate Infenfibles ( o ’ 1: r, ;</l>
	<l>And ftrikes a reverend awe upon the Soul, r - i  t - V</l>
	<l>Nothing is found fo lovely. j </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Thou (peak’ft prettily, I think love</l>
	<l>Indeed has infpir’d thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Thefe were the flatteries, Sir, (he us’d to me, \</l>
	<l>Of her it was I learn’d to fpeak, and figh v ; ;</l>
	<l>And look, as oft you fay, I do on you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Why then, it feems.(he made returns > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>dor.</speaker>
	<l> Ah ! Sir, ’twas I that firft wasbleft, .1 ,</l>
	<l>I firft the happy object was belov’d, t : ; .</l>
	<l>For’twasaperfon, Sir, fo much above me 5 1</l>
	<l>It had been fin to’ve rais’d my eyes to her 5 r</l>
	<l>Or by a glance, or figh, betray my pain :</l>
	<l>But oh ! when with a thoufand foft exprefiions, . ,</l>
	<l>She did incourage me to fpeak of Love! ; .</l>
	<l>—My god, how foon extravagant I grew, ?</l>
	<l>And told fo oft the (lory of my paflion , ) </l>
	<l>That (lie grew weary of the repeated tale, 1</l>
	<l>And punififd my prefumption with a ftrange neglecti [JVeeps. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> How my good Phillibert >  , " </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>clor.</speaker>
	<l> Would fufter me to fee her face no more. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> That was pity, without a fault/ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Alas, Sir, I was guilty of no crime.</l>
	<l>But that of having told her how I lov’d her 5</l>
	<l>For all I had I facrific’d to her 5</l>
	<l>—Poor worthless treafures, to any but a Lover 5</l>
	<l>And fuch you know accept the meaneft things:</l>
	<l>Love and a true Devotion, do prefent,</l>
	<l>When file was prefent, I found a thouland ways</l>
	<l>To let her know how much I was her Have 5</l>
	<l>And abfent Hill invented new ones.</l>
	<l>And quite neglefred all my little bufinels 5</l>
	<l>Counting the tedious moments of the day</l>
	<l>By fighs and tears 5 thought it an age to night,</l>
	<l>Whofe darkness might fecure our happy meeting:</l>
	<l>But we (hall meet no more on thefe kind terms. [Sicks.</l>
	<l>I Fred.</l>
	<l>C$9) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Come, do not weep, fweet youth, thou art too young</l>
	<l>To have thy blooming cheeks blafted with farrow 5</l>
	<l>Thou wilt out-grow thischildifh inclination,</l>
	<l>And (halt fee beauties here, whole every glance</l>
	<l>Kindles new fires, and quite expel the old. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Oh never Sir.</l>
	<l>Fred . When I was firft in Love, I thought fo too.</l>
	<l>But now with equal ardoyr,</l>
	<l>Idoat upon each new and beauteous objeft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> And quite forget the old ></l>
	<l>Fred . Not fo, but when I fee them o’re again,</l>
	<l>I find I love them as 1 did before. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Oh God forbid, I Ihould be fo inconfiftaot $</l>
	<l>Vo, Sir, though (he be falfe (he has my heart.</l>
	<l>And I can dye, but not redeem the vittim. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Away you little Fool, you make me fad</l>
	<l>By this refblve, but rieinftructyou better. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> I would not make you fad for all the world;</l>
	<l>Sir, I will Sing, or Dance, do any thing</l>
	<l>That may divert you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> I thank thee Phillibert, and will accept</l>
	<l>Thy bounty 3 perhaps it may allay thy griess a while too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Ile call the Mufick, Sir. QSAe goes out. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> This Boy has Grange agreements in him.</l>
	<l>Enter Cloris with Mufick</l>
	<l>she bids them and Dances a Jig.</l>
	<l>This was wondrous kind my prety Phillibert.</l>
	<l>Enter Page. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Page.</speaker>
	<l> Lorenzo , my Lord, begs admittance. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> He may come in:</l>
	<l>Enter Lorenzo.</l>
	<l>—Well Lorenzo , whats the news with thee }</l>
	<l>—How goes the price of Beauty, hah? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, that queftion is a propo to</l>
	<l>What I have to (ay 5 this paper will anfwer your</l>
	<l>Queftion Sir—— [Gives hint a Paper, he reads</l>
	<l>—Hah,</l>
	<l>( 59 ) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l>gates oh PhilL</l>
	<l>—-Hah, I vow to gacfa lovely youth.</l>
	<l>But what makes he here with Ftederic\ )</l>
	<l>This (tripling may chance to mar my market of Women rtOW—</l>
	<l>Tis a fine lad, how plump and white he is 5 [Afidc</l>
	<l>Would I could meet him fome where ith dark,</l>
	<l>I’de have a fling at him, and try whether I</l>
	<l>Were right Florentine, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Well, Sir, where be thefe beauties. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Tie conduft you to them. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> What’s the fellow that brings them ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A Grecian, I think, or fomething.</l>
	<l>Fred . Beauties from Greece, man! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> W hy, let them be from the Devil,</l>
	<l>So they be new, and fine, what need we care 5</l>
	<l>—But you muft go to night. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> I am not in a very good condition</l>
	<l>To make vifits of that kind. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> However fee them, andif you like them.</l>
	<l>You may oblige the fellow to a longer ftay.</l>
	<l>For I know they are handfome. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> That’s the only thing thou art judge of</l>
	<l>—Well go you and prepare them.</l>
	<l>And Phillibert thou (halt along with me 5</l>
	<l>I’le have thy judgment too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Good Heaven, how falfe he is! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> What time will your Highness come? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Two hours hence. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> So then I (hall have time to have a bout</l>
	<l>With this gilting hufwife Isabella> [ Afide .</l>
	<l>For my fingers itch to be at her. [e. Lorenzo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Not know me yet5 cannot this face inform him.</l>
	<l>My fighs, nor eyes, my accent, nor my tale 5 '</l>
	<l>Had he one thought of me, he muft have found me out ></l>
	<l>—Yes, yes, ’tis certain lam miferable 5.</l>
	<l>He’s going now to fee fome frefher beauties.</l>
	<l>And I, he fays, muft be a witness of it 5 v</l>
	<l>This gives me wounds, painful as thole of Love: A « »</l>
	<l>me women now would'find a thoiifand Plots</l>
	<l>I 2</l>
	<l>[Afide</l>
	<l>[Ex. Frfed.</l>
	<l>From fo much grief as I have, but I’m dull 5</l>
	<l>Yet He to Laura, and advife with her.</l>
	<l>Where I will tell her fuch a heavy a tale.</l>
	<l>As (hall oblige her to a kind concern :</l>
	<l>'—This may do 3 I’le tell her of this thought,</l>
	<l>Thisisthe firH: of Art Fever thought on 5</l>
	<l>And if this prove a fruitless remedy,</l>
	<l>The next, I need not ftudy, how to dye. [Exeunt.</l>
	<l>, t SCENE IV.</l>
	<l>Enter Lorenzo, meets Guilliam,  pajfes by him, and takes no</l>
	<l>notice of him. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> How now Manners a few ?</l>
	<l>GniL I cry you heartily. Sir, I did not fee you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Well, Sirrah, the news. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Gull.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, the Gentlevyoman whom you fent me to fays,</l>
	<l>That’s he’le meet you here. , _ ’ V ' </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> That’s well, thou may’ft come to be a Statesman</l>
	<l>In time, thou art a fellow..0/ fo quick difpatch: ,</l>
	<l>But harky, Sifraii, tfiere are a few leftons I muft ]</l>
	<l>Concerning offices of this nature y</l>
	<l>But another time for that; but—</l>
	<l> - , , Enter Isabella WV|illct.</l>
	<l>Ijah'. Here he is, andprethee when thou feeft ipjip in</l>
	<l>My chamber, go andtell my Lord,</l>
	<l>Under pretence pf the care yoi have ofthe hpnpur offtis Boufe.</l>
	<l>, Val. I warranf you,'let me alone 1 for a tale, </l>
	<l>And a lye at the end on’t 5 whichThai 1 not. oye-r much</l>
	<l>InCnfehiffi,m- —t— ---- - 1 1    </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>I muft learn youj</l>
	<l>tir i;</l>
	<l>[ivhijpers.</l>
	<l>To</l>
	<l>Are</l>
	<l>r r xr u  j r  ' TTr;115D?.tJ r 33 ] — </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifab.</speaker>
	<l> You have a mind toloqfe your opportunity again,. :</l>
	<l>As you did laft night, have ve riot > . ; \ !</l>
	<l>Pray God your own ftadow'/care you hot, ' :i u 5 ! . .</l>
	<l>As it did then '</l>
	<l>won pmlunfj r.u/Ti oTnow won no mow</l>
	<l>s i No</l>
	<l>...  » ' . -   ';  ' </l>
	<l>No body meant you harm then, nor now. : </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Art thou in earneft ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Are you in earneft } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Yes that I am, and that Clarina hall find</l>
	<l>If I once come to her. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Come, leave your frippery jefts and come in. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Guilliam , be fure you attend me here,</l>
	<l>And who ever you fee, fay nothing 5 the beft on’t is.</l>
	<l>Thou art not much known. [Tfab. and Lor. go in. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Guil.</speaker>
	<l> Well, I fee there is nothing butfoutering</l>
	<l>Tth this Town 5 wo’d our Lucia were here too for me,</l>
	<l>For all the Maids fmeet with are fo giglifh</l>
	<l>And fcornful, that a man, as I am,</l>
	<l>Gets nothing but flouts and flings from them :</l>
	<l>Ghfor the little kind Lass that lives</l>
	<l>Under the Hill, of whom the Song was made 5</l>
	<l>Which becaufel have nothing elfe to do,</l>
	<l>I will fing over now 3 hum, hum, ' [To fume Tunc- like him.</l>
	<l>«; <</l>
	<l>The Song for Guilliam.</l>
	<l>In a Cottage by the Mountain ,</l>
	<l>Lives a very prety Maid, '</l>
	<l>Who lay fieeping by a Fountain ,</l>
	<l>'Underneath a Mirtle Jfjade ,</l>
	<l>Her Petticoat of wanton Sarcenet , </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>The .</speaker>
	<l> Amorous wind about did move ,</l>
	<l>And quite unveil’d,</l>
	<l>. And quite\unveil'd the Throne of Love ,</l>
	<l>And quite unveil’d the Throne of Love.</l>
	<l>’Tisfomething cold. Fie go take a Niperkin of Wine. [Goes out.</l>
	<l>. i . -4</l>
	<l>M'</l>
	<l>morn 01</l>
	<l>\ A-</l>
	<l>Enter Ifab. and Lor. above , affrighted into the Bale one.</l>
	<l>This was fottitk'oftHine 4 ,! #ill be hang’delfe. ‘ r </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Oh, Lie be fworh you wrong me 5 T</l>
	<l>Alas, I’m undone byt. : [kx\i. at the door knocks. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Open the door thou naughty woman. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Oh oh, what fhafll do? whabfhMl I; db-> : T.  : v  \ f </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Open the door I fay. f ®8  3:;n  c -</l>
	<l>S Lor . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Oh Visa damnable leap out at this IctIeone, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> And yet you are a dead man if you fee hiPV </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> Impudence, will you open the door }</l>
	<l>Ifab I will. Sir, immediately. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Devife (ome way to let me down,</l>
	<l>Or I will throw thee out 5 nolader of Ropes, no device ?</l>
	<l>—If a man would not forfwear whoring for the future,</l>
	<l>That is in my condition, lam no true Gentleman. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Open, or I will break the door. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>lfab.</speaker>
	<l> Hold the door, andfwearluftily that you</l>
	<l>Are my Husband, and I will in the mean time</l>
	<l>Provide for your fafety, £ He holds the doom</l>
	<l>Though I can think of none but the (heets from the bed. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Any thing to lave my life 5</l>
	<l>—Sir you may believe me upon my honour,</l>
	<l>I am lawful husband to Iftbella 5</l>
	<l>And have no defignsupon your houfeor honour. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> this while fattens the fleets , which are to be ftppofd</l>
	<l>from the bed , to the Balcone. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Thou art (ome Villain. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> No, Sir, I am an honeft man, and married lawfully. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Who art thou > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Haft thou done ></l>
	<l>Ifab . Yes, but you rauft venture hard. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Tis Lorenzo , Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A Pox on her, now am I afham’dtoall eternity.</l>
	<l>Ifab . Sir, let me beg youi take his word and oath to night.</l>
	<l>And to morrow I will iatisfie you. £ Lot. gets down by the fleets.</l>
	<l>AnU Look you make this good.</l>
	<l>Or you (hall both dearly pay for’t. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Iam alive, yes, yes, all’s whole and found.</l>
	<l>Which is a mercy, I can tell yo\\£</l>
	<l>This is whoring now: may J turn</l>
	<l>If I could not find in myhearttpdp penance</l>
	<l>In CamphirePpffet, this month for this: by</l>
	<l>—Well, l muft to this Merchant of JLovei. A</l>
	<l>And I would gladly be thqre before the Frktcei; \j . -v</l>
	<l>For fines I have mift here, .vn: I iQ-d .a</l>
	<l>I</l>
	<l>(ct</l>
	<l>I (hall be Amorous enough.</l>
	<l>And then I'le provide for Frederic 4 $</l>
	<l>For’tis but juft, although he be my Mafter,</l>
	<l>That I in thefe Ragoufts (hould be his tafter. [Exeunt.</l>
	<l>SCENE V.</l>
	<l>Enter Ifinena with a veil. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Alberto is not come yet , fure he loves me 5</l>
	<l>But tis not tears, and knees, that can confirm me b</l>
	<l>No, I rauft be convinc’d by better argument,</l>
	<l>—Deceit, if ever thou a guide wer’t made</l>
	<l>To Amorous hearts, aflift a Love-fick Maid.</l>
	<l>Enter Alberto. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Your pleafure, Madam?</l>
	<l>—Oh that (he would be brie£</l>
	<l> And fend me quickly from her,</l>
	<l>For her eyes will overthrow" my purpofe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Alberto , do you love me ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> No. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>jfm.</speaker>
	<l> No, have you deceiv’d me then ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Neither Clarina 5 when I told you fo.</l>
	<l>By Heaven twas perfedt truth. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> And what have 1 done fince (hould</l>
	<l>Merit your dif-efteem > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Nothing but what has rais’d it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Torai(eyourefteem,thenit (eems,i$</l>
	<l>To leflen your love 5 or as moft gallants are $</l>
	<l>You’re but pleas’d with what you have not $</l>
	<l>And love a Miftriss with great paffton, till you find /</l>
	<l>Your felf belov’d again, and then you hate her. - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> You wrong my Soul extremely, i</l>
	<l>Tis not of that ungrateful nature b </l>
	<l>Toloveme,is to me a greater charm \</l>
	<l>Then that of Wit or Beauty. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> I’me glad on’t Sir, then I have pleafant news for you,</l>
	<l>I know a Lady, and a Virgin too.</l>
	<l>That</l>
	<l>W</l>
	<l>That loves you with fuch paflion, o ;.y " ;</l>
	<l>As has oblig’d me to become' her Advocate. 1 V : : </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> I am very much oblig’d to her.</l>
	<l>If there be any fuch. , s  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Upon my life there is j I am in earned.</l>
	<l>The Lady is my Sifter too.. r </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> How, claritta , this from you? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Nay, I have promis’d her, that you fhall lovie her too,</l>
	<l>Since both her birth and beauty merits you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Away falfe woman: I love your Sifter l</l>
	<l>No, I will hate ye both. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Why fo angry ?</l>
	<l>Alas, it is againftmy will I do it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Did you betray my faith, when ’twasfo eafie</l>
	<l>To give a credit to your tale of Love? </l>
	<l>— Oh woman, faithless woman! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Alberto , with a world of ftiame I own</l>
	<l>That I then lov’d you, and muft do fo ftill 5</l>
	<l>But fincethat Love muft be accounted criminal.</l>
	<l>And that a world of danger do’s attend it,</l>
	<l>I am refolv’d, though I can never quit it.</l>
	<l>To change it into kind efteem for you 5</l>
	<l>And would Ally you, Sir, as near tome.</l>
	<l>As our unkind Stars will permit me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> I thank you. Madam, oh what a ftiame it is</l>
	<l>To be out-done in Vertue, as in Love! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Another favour I muft beg of you, </l>
	<l>That you will tell Antonio what is paft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> How mean ydu Madam ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Why, that I Love you Sir,</l>
	<l>And how I have deceiv’d him into confidence. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> This is ftrange 5 you cannot mean it fure. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> When I intend to be extremely good,</l>
	<l>I would not have a fecret fin within,  - ; j</l>
	<l>Though old, and yet repented too. j no Sir,</l>
	<l>Confeffion always goes with Penitence. \ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Do you repent you that you lov’d me then? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Not fo5 but that I did abufe Ant oh jo. ; r : 1 i</l>
	<l>k Alb.</l>
	<l>(5) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> And can you think that this will cure his jealoufie > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Doubtlessit will, when he knows how needless’tiv,  ,</l>
	<l>For when they're mod fecure, they’re mod betray’d 3</l>
	<l>Befides,I did but ad the part he made.</l>
	<l>And ills he forces fure, he’le not upbraid. Gofeekout Antoni. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Youhaveo’recomeme, Madam, every way,.</l>
	<l>And this your laft command I can obey 3</l>
	<l>Your Sifter too lie fee, and will efteem,</l>
	<l>But you’ve my heart, which I can ne’re redeem. [_Ex. fever ally.</l>
	<l>V Z</l>
	<l>A C T. V. S C E N E. I</l>
	<l>Enter Laura and Cloris likg a Boy as before.</l>
	<l>It chanc’d Prince FredericJZcame unto our Village,</l>
	<l>On fome reports were made him of my beauty,</l>
	<l>Attended only by the noble Curtivs :</l>
	<l>They found me in the Church at my Devotion,</l>
	<l>Whom Frederick foon diftinguifh’d from the reft 3</l>
	<l>Hekneel’d down by me, and inftead of Prayer,</l>
	<l>He fell to Praife 3 but ’twas my beauty only 3</l>
	<l>—That I could tell you, of my ftrange furprife l</l>
	<l>My zeal was all diforder’d, and my eyes,</l>
	<l>Fed onthefalfe, not real facrifice3</l>
	<l>—I wanted Art my fentiments to hide, ]</l>
	<l>Which from my eye$ and blufties foon he fpy’d. j </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lad.</speaker>
	<l> And did you know him then ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Not till he left me 3</l>
	<l>—But to be (hort. Madam, we parted there,</l>
	<l>But e’re he went, he whifper’d in my ear.</l>
	<l>And figh’d, ah Cloris ! e’re you do depart.</l>
	<l>Tell me, where ’tis you will difpofemy heart ?</l>
	<l>—Pray give meleavetovifit it again.</l>
	<l>K</l>
	<l>Your</l>
	<l>..(«)</l>
	<l>Your eyes that gave, can only eafe my pain:</l>
	<l>I, only blufhing gave him myconfents.</l>
	<l>He paid his thanks in fighs, and from me went.</l>
	<l>That right, alas, I took but little reft 3 1</l>
	<l>Tfie tie wand ftrange diforder in my breaft, (</l>
	<l>Can, Madam, only by your felf be gueft. J </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> I’lenot deny that, i’m'e a Lover too,</l>
	<l>And can imagine what was Felt by you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> No fooner did the Welcom day appear,</l>
	<l>But Lucia brought me word the Prince was there</l>
	<l>His very name diforder’d me much more.</l>
	<l>Then did his fight or touch the day before3</l>
	<l>So foon my rifing Love grew up to power 3</l>
	<l>So foon he did become my Conquerour:</l>
	<l>—How pale and trembling, when he did appear</l>
	<l>I grew, he too had marks of love and fear 3</l>
	<l>—But I‘le omit the many vifits paid,</l>
	<l>The unvalued Prefents, and the Oaths he made.</l>
	<l>My kind dilputes on all his letters writ,</l>
	<l>How all my doubts were anfwer’d by his wit 3</l>
	<l>How oft he vow’d to marry me, vyhilft I,</l>
	<l>Durft not believe the pleafing-perjury 3</l>
	<l>-And only tellyou, that one night he came,.</l>
	<l>Led by defigns of an impatient flame 3</l>
	<l>When all the houfe was filently afleep.</l>
	<l>Except my felf, who loves fad watch did keep 3</l>
	<l>Arm’dwithhis Ponyard, and his breaft ali bare 3</l>
	<l>His face all pale with reftless Jove and fear3</l>
	<l>So many wild and frantick things he laid.</l>
	<l>And fo much grief and paffion too betray’d.</l>
	<l>So often vow’d heed finifti there his life.</l>
	<l>If I refus’d him to become his W ife 3</l>
	<l>That I half dying, laid it fhouldbe (03</l>
	<l>Which though I fear’d, oh how f wifht it too L</l>
	<l>Both proftrate on the ground i’th’ face of Heaven,</l>
	<l>His vows to me, and mine to him were given 3</l>
	<l>—And then, oh then, what did t not refign!</l>
	<l>( 6 7 ')</l>
	<l>With the afFurance that the Prince was mine. ' [Htyepf. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Poor doris > how I pity thee ! : : '</l>
	<l>Since fate has treated me with equal rigour 5</l>
	<l>— Curtius is banith’d, Frederick (till purfues me,</l>
	<l>And by a cruel Father I’me confin’d,</l>
	<l>And cannot go to ferve my felf or thee. [ [One </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> With out. Sifter Laura, Sifter. n / , r r .. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau .</speaker>
	<l> It it my brother, would he would be kind</l>
	<l>And fet us free, he (hall not fee thee.</l>
	<l>And Tie perfvvadehim.</l>
	<l>[As Jhe puts Cloris7»/0 her Clofet , Enter Lor. with ft Letter</l>
	<l>Clor, Hah, locking her CIo(et! now were I a right .</l>
	<l>Italian hould I grow jealous, and enrag’d at</l>
	<l>I knew not what: hah Sifter!</l>
	<l>What are you doing here ?</l>
	<l>Open your Cabinet and let me fee’t. . </l>
	<l>Lau, Sir, ’tis in diforder, and not worth your feeing now. t</l>
	<l>Lor, ’Tis fo, I care not for'that,Tie fee’t. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Pray do not brother. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Your denial makesme the more inquifitive. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tis but my faying, he camefrom the Prince, [Aflde.</l>
	<l>And he dares not take it ill —-here Sir. ;; [Gives him the Key. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> And here’s for you too . a Letter from Curtius</l>
	<l>And therefore I would not open it 5 I took it up</l>
	<l>At the Poft-houfe. [she reads, and feemspleafed.</l>
	<l>Now if this (hould prove fome furly Gallant of her’s.</l>
	<l>And give me a fla(ho’re the face for peeping,</l>
	<l>I were but rightly ferv’d 5</l>
	<l>And why the Devil (hould I expectmy Sifter (hould</l>
	<l>Have more vertue then my felf ></l>
	<l>She’s the fame fle(h and blood? or why, becaufe</l>
	<l>She’s the weaker Veflel 5</l>
	<l>Should all the unreafonable burthen of the honour</l>
	<l>Of our houfe, as they call it.</l>
	<l>Be laid on her (houlders, whilft we may commit</l>
	<l>A thoufand villanies 5 but ’tis fo-</l>
	<l>Here open the dobr, r 1 </l>
	<l>K 2</l>
	<l>w</l>
	<l>Tie put her before me however. [she opens the door and </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, ’tis Phillibert from the Prince. brings out Cloris. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Why how now youngfter, I fee you intend</l>
	<l>To thrive by your many trades 5</l>
	<l>So foon, fofoon, ifaith 5 but firrah,</l>
	<l>This is my Sifter and your Princes Miftress,</l>
	<l>Take notice of that. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> I know not what you mean. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, you cannot deceive me fo$</l>
	<l>And you were right ferv’d, you would be made he</l>
	<l>For nothing but the great Turks Seraglio . ' </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> You miftakemy bufinels Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Your blufhes give you the lye Sirrah 5</l>
	<l>But for the Princes fake, and another reafon I have,</l>
	<l>I will pardon you for once. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> He has not done a fault, and needs it not. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Was he not alone with thee ?</l>
	<l>And is not that enough: well I fee I am no Italian</l>
	<l>In Punctilioes of honourable revenge.</l>
	<l>There is but one experiment left to prove my felf fo ></l>
	<l>And if that fail. Fie ev’n renounce my Country.</l>
	<l>-Boy, harkey—there is a certain kindness</l>
	<l>You may do me, and get your pardon for being found here..</l>
	<l>Clor . You (hall command me any thing. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Prethee how long haft thou been fet up for thy fel£</l>
	<l>Hah ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> As how Sir? ;; </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Poh,thou underftand’ft me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Indeed I do not Sir, what is’t you mean? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A fmooth fac’d Boy, and ask fuch a queftion,.</l>
	<l>Fie, fie, this ignorance was ill counterfeited</l>
	<l>Tome thatunderftand the world. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Explain your felf Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Look,tenor twenty Piftols will do you</l>
	<l>No hurt, will it?</l>
	<l>Clor . Not any Sir. _< </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Why fo 5 ’tis well anything will make thee</l>
	<l>Apprehend.. . -</l>
	<l>USIL'C</l>
	<l>Clor </l>
	<l>m </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> I (hall be glad to ferve you, Sir, without that fee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> That’s kindly faid-</l>
	<l>I fee a man muft not be too eafie of belief: had I been fo.</l>
	<l>This Boy would have been at what do ye mean Sir 5</l>
	<l>And Lord I underftand you not:</l>
	<l>Well Phillebert, here’searneft to bind the bargain 5</l>
	<l>I am now in haft, when I fee thee next, [[Loren, whifpcrs</l>
	<l>I’le tell thee more. to Laura.</l>
	<l>do. This ’tis to be a Favourite now 5</l>
	<l>I warrant you I muft do him fomegood office to the Prince,</l>
	<l>Which I’le be fure to do. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Nay it muft be done, for (he has us’d me bafely,</l>
	<l>Oh tis a baggage. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lan.</speaker>
	<l> Let me alone to revenge you on Ifabclla ,</l>
	<l>Get me but from this Imprisonment. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> I will 5 whilftl hold the old man in a difpute,</l>
	<l>Do you two get away 3 but be fure thou pay ’ft her home. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lan.</speaker>
	<l> I warrant you, Sir, this was happy 5</l>
	<l>Now (hall I fee Curtins. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Phillibert, I advife you to have a care of</l>
	<l>Wenching: ’twill fpoil a good face,</l>
	<l>And mar your better market of the two. [Ex. Lor. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Gome let us haft, and by the way, I’le tell thee</l>
	<l>Of a means that may make us all happy. [Exeunt.</l>
	<l>SCENE IT.</l>
	<l>Enter Alberto Melancholy. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio (aid he would be here,</l>
	<l>I’me impatient till he come.—</l>
	<l>Enter Antonio.  - </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> //£erto,Ihavefuchaprojettforthee ! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Hah- [Gazes. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> What ails thee, art thou well> </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> No. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Where art thou Sick > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> At heart Antonio , poyfon’d by thy jealoufie 3</l>
	<l>Oh thou haft ruin‘d me, undone my quiet,</l>
	<l>And from a man of reafonable vertue</l>
	<l>Has brought me to a wild diftracted Lover. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Explain your felf. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Thou’ft taught me, friend, to love Ci<irin.t }</l>
	<l>Not as I promis’d thee to feigu, but fo,</l>
	<l>That Ij unlessl do pofless that objetft, )</l>
	<l>I thinkmuft dye} at beft bemiferable. \ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> How Sir, have I done this? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Yes Antonio , thou haft done this,. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> My dear Alberto j faid you that you lov’d her ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, Antonio, againft my will I do 5</l>
	<l>As much againft my will, as when I told her fo 5</l>
	<l>Urg’d by thy needless ftratagem. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Name it no more, it was an idlefault.</l>
	<l>Which I do fo repent me.</l>
	<l>That if you find I ftould relapfe again.</l>
	<l>Kill me, and let me perifh with my weakness:</l>
	<l>And were that true you tell me of your paflion.</l>
	<l>Sure I ftiould wifh to dye, to make you happy. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> That’s kindly faid, and I fubmit to you,, > i</l>
	<l>And am content to be out-done in Amity. . , ’ - ; P ' </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, I’lerefign my claims and leave the world }</l>
	<l>Alberto , ’tis unkind to think I would be happy"</l>
	<l>By ways muftruine you}</l>
	<l>But fure you tell me this but only to afflift me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tis truth Antonio I do love Clarinet</l>
	<l>And what is yet far worfe for thy repofe.</l>
	<l>Believe my felf fo blefttobe belov’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> How, to be belov’d by her!</l>
	<l>—Oh dire effectsof jealoufie ! - ...[ : ' .  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> All that you faw to day was: only-feign’d.</l>
	<l>To let you fee, that even your eyes.and earst vr:t ’ < v</l>
	<l>Might be impos’d upon. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Can it bepoffible!. ; ; . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Andnowfhe thinks fte is enough reveng’d 5 .n /i</l>
	<l>And lets, you know in her feign’d fcoi#Q me rr \ . /</l>
	<l>That all your Heights and cunningBrQbutvuin yu.-j/i jA</l>
	<l>O )</l>
	<l>She has deceiv’d them all, and by that Art,</l>
	<l>Gives you a confidence, and meaheart. < </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I muft confess it is but juft in her</l>
	<l>To punifh thus the errors of my fear 3</l>
	<l>I do forgive her, from my Soul I do.</l>
	<l>—But, Sir, what fatisfaction’s this to you ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Marina happy. Tie from Court retire,</l>
	<l>And by that abfence quench my hopeless fire 5</l>
	<l>War, I will make my Miftress, who maybe.</l>
	<l>Perhaps more kind then (he has been to me ,</l>
	<l>Where though I cannot conquer, ’twil allow</l>
	<l>That I may dye 5 that’s more then this will do. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> — Why did you, Sir, betray my weaknels to her }</l>
	<l>Though ’twas but what I did deferve from you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> By all that’s good fheknew the plot before,</l>
	<l>From Isabella , who it feemso’re heard us.</l>
	<l>When you once preft me to’t:</l>
	<l>And had we wanted vertue, thou’dft been loft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I own the Crime 5</l>
	<l>And firft I beg thy Pardon,</l>
	<l>And after that, will get it from Marina 5</l>
	<l>Which done, Ile wait upon thee to the Camp,</l>
	<l>And fuffer one years Penance for this fin,</l>
	<l>Unless I could divert this refolution.</l>
	<l>By a propofal Marina bid me make you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> What was it Sir } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> I have a Sifter, Friend, a handfom Virgin,</l>
	<l>Rich, witty, and I think (he’s vertuoustoo 5</l>
	<l>Return’d laft week from St. Teretias Monaftery. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Sure any thing that is to thee Alli’d,</l>
	<l>Muft find a more then bare refpeft from me;</l>
	<l>But it is certain I ne’re fhall Love again,</l>
	<l>And have refolv’d never to Marry any.</l>
	<l>Where Intereft, and not Love muft joyn our hands. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> You cannot tell what power there lies in beauty 5</l>
	<l>Come you (hall fee her, and if after that,</l>
	<l>You find you cannot love her,</l>
	<l>We’le both to Candia, where we both will prove</l>
	<l>Rivals</l>
	<l>( 7 )</l>
	<l>Rivals in Honour, as we're now in Love:</l>
	<l>—But I’de forgot to tell thee what I came for 5</l>
	<l>I mart this evening beg your company.</l>
	<l>Nay, and perhaps your Sword 3 come along with me,</l>
	<l>And by the way Tie tell you the adventure. £ Exeunt.</l>
	<l>SCENE. III.</l>
	<l>The Lodgings ofCuvtms.</l>
	<l>Enter Curtius and Pietro difguifed as before . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> I wonder we hear no news yet of the Prince,</l>
	<l>I hope he’lecome, Pietro be the Bravo’s ready.</l>
	<l>And the Curtizans? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, they’l be here immediately,all well dreft too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> They be thofe Bravo’s that did belong to me ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, Sir, the fame 5</l>
	<l>But Antonio is their Patron.</l>
	<l>Curt . They be ftout and fecret $ ’tis well.</l>
	<l>Is the Mufick and all things ready ?</l>
	<l>For I’le not be feen till my part is to be play’d 5 </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> What Arms have they ?</l>
	<l>Piftols Sir, would you have other ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> No, I have not yet conftder’d how to kill him,</l>
	<l>Nor fcarce refolv’d to do fo any way,</l>
	<l>What makes this ftrange irrefolution in me?</l>
	<l>—Sure tis the force of facred Amity,</l>
	<l>Which but too ftrictly was obferv’d by me:</l>
	<l>—My Prince, and Friend, my Wife and Sifter too 5</l>
	<l>Shall not thofe laft, thepowerful firft out-do:</l>
	<l>My Honour and my Love are there ingag’d.</l>
	<l>And here, by tyes of duty, I’me oblig’d :</l>
	<l>I fatisfie but thefe, if he muft bleed 5</l>
	<l>But ruine the whole Dukedom in the deed.</l>
	<l>The hopeful Heir of all their noble fpoils.</l>
	<l>And joy and recompence of all their toyls.</l>
	<l>—Why fo was Chris } Laura too, to me.</l>
	<l>Which</l>
	<l>( 73 )</l>
	<l>Which both were ravifht from me,Prince,by th eefUChocwithin. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Viet.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, they be the Bravo’s and Curtezans. QPiet. Coes out. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tisvvel/, I need not talk with them.</l>
	<l>They underftand their work.</l>
	<l>Piet . They do my Lord, and fhall be ready at your damp 3</l>
	<l>They are all Neopolitans you know Sir, </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Are they the better for that ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> Much Sir, a Venetian will turn to your enemy,</l>
	<l>If he will give him but a Soufe more then you have done 5</l>
	<l>And your Millanoije are fit for nothing but to</l>
	<l>R< b the Poll: or Carrier 5 a Genouefe too</l>
	<l>Will fooner kill by Ufury, then Sword or Piftol,</l>
	<l>A Roman fit for nothing but a fpy. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Well, Sir, you are pleafant with my Countrymen </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> Pie be (o with my own too Sir, and tell you.</l>
	<l>That a Maltan , who pretends to fo much honour</l>
	<l>And gravity, are fit only to rob their neighbours</l>
	<l>With pretence of Piety.</l>
	<l>—And a Cicilian fo taken up with Plots,</l>
	<l>How to kill his Vice-Roy, that it keeps them</l>
	<l>From being Rogues to a less degree 5</l>
	<l>But I have done. Sir, and beg your perdon. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Did’ft leave the Letter, I commanded thee.</l>
	<l>For Laura ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Piet.</speaker>
	<l> I did my Lord. Enter Lorenzo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Well, here’s the’Prince juft coming. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Pray Sir condud him in,</l>
	<l>I’me ready for him. Ex. Curt, and Piet.</l>
	<l>Enter the Prince, conduced by two Wo-')</l>
	<l>menin Mafquerade , with Lights , he en-sEx. two Women,</l>
	<l>deavouring to take off their Masks. J</l>
	<l>He walks about while this Song is ffinging.</l>
	<l>. » > t </l>
	<l>v'</l>
	<l>- -  ’ ' ,  - J</l>
	<l>What is the recompence of War 0</l>
	<l>But foft as wanton Peace .?</l>
	<l>What the be si Balfom to our fears «?</l>
	<l>But that which Venus gave to Mars,</l>
	<l>When he was circled in a kind embrace .</l>
	<l>' -  ' L Behold</l>
	<l>( 74 )..</l>
	<l>Behold a Trince who never yet</l>
	<l>IVas vanquijht in the Field j</l>
	<l>A while his Glories mu FI forget ,</l>
	<l>And lay his Laurels at the feet</l>
	<l>Of fome fair Femalpower , to whom he leyield. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> What’s this the preparation ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, fo it fhould feem 5 but had you met</l>
	<l>With fomany defeats as I have done to night,</l>
	<l>You would willingly excufethis Ceremony.</l>
	<l>» .</l>
	<l>Aiffich fir the Dance.</l>
	<l>Enter Antonio with Ifmena, Alberto with Clarina, Laura and</l>
	<l>Cloris with two men more, and all drejl in Mafquerade with</l>
	<l>vizards } they Dance. The Prince Jets doivn y the Dance being</l>
	<l>done j they retire to one (tdej and Alberto comes and prejents</l>
	<l>him Clarina } and bows and retires j who puts off her Maskj></l>
	<l>and puts it on again and retires . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> She’s wondrous fair 5</l>
	<l>Sure in his whole Cabal he cannot (how a fairer— </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> She refembles clarina 3 I wifh your Highness</l>
	<l>Would fee further} and then perhaps, this would</l>
	<l>Fall to my lot, for I love her for likeness fake.</l>
	<l>£ Antonio prejents Ifmena, and retires as the other.</l>
	<l>Fred . This I confess out-does the others.</l>
	<l>An Innocency dwells upon her face.</l>
	<l>That’s ftrangely taking, is it not Lorenzo > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> To fay truth, (he is very fine indeed. [ They prejent Laura. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Hah 1 I am amaz’d } fee Lorenzo</l>
	<l>Doft thou not know that face ?</l>
	<l>Lor , A my confidence and foul ’tis my own Sifter Laura }</l>
	<l>Why how now Miftress,</l>
	<l>Do things go thus with you ifaith ></l>
	<l>\_she JJjahes her hand as riot under Handing him . </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, (lie underftandsyou not. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Is it not Laura then </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> No Sir, it is a ftranger.</l>
	<l>Fred ,</l>
	<l>( 75 ) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Let her be what (he will, I’le have her.</l>
	<l>[Fred .feemsto talkrohen fiean freersinGrimaffes </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> There have been examples in the world</l>
	<l>Of the good offices done by a Brother to a Sifter 5</l>
	<l>But they are very rare here.</l>
	<l>And therefore will furely be the more acceptable 3</l>
	<l>Well Sir, have you fix’d, that I may chufe ?</l>
	<l>Fred . I have, and had hethoufandsmore, [Lor.cJ 1 to Gar.</l>
	<l>I would refufe them all for this fair Creature.</l>
	<l>Enter Pietro. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Viet.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, all things are ready as you defire.</l>
	<l>But my Maftermuft firftfpeak with you alone. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> About the price I’le warrant you 5</l>
	<l>Let him come in 3 [.Allgo out but Fred, to him Curt.</l>
	<l>—Are you the Mafter of the Ceremony > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Iam. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Be fpeedy then, and by my impatiency</l>
	<l>To be with that agreeable ftranger, guess at my</l>
	<l>Approbation of the Ladies, and which Jchufe. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Your mighty heat, Sir, will be foon allay’d.</l>
	<l>Fred . Shall it ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Yes Sir, it (hall, for you muft dye.</l>
	<l>Fred . Sure thou art mad to tell me fo, who e’re thoube’ft,</l>
	<l>Whilft I have this about me. [Dram. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> That, Sir, you draw in vain 3 ftand off-, [offers a Pijlol. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> What new conceited preparation’s this } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, when you know this face, it will inform you.</l>
	<l>[Pulls off his falfe Beard.</l>
	<l>Fred . Curtius! I am betray’d, oh villain ! [Offers to fight. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Ho within there—</l>
	<l>[He calls , and all the Masked men come out , and offer the</l>
	<l>Pifiols at Frederick. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Hold, I am the Prince of Florence. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Thefe, Sir, are Rogues, and have no fence of ought.</l>
	<l>But mifchief in their Souls 3 r</l>
	<l>Gold is their Prince and God,—go, begon— [ffhey withdraw.</l>
	<l>—See, Sir, I can command them. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Curtius , why doft thou deal thus treacheroufly with me ?</l>
	<l>L 2 Did</l>
	<l>(7-0</l>
	<l>Did I not offer thee to fight thee fairly ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Cnrt.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tis like the injuries, Sir, that you have done me.</l>
	<l>Pardon me if my griess make me too rude,</l>
	<l>Andin courfe terms lay all your fins beforeyou.</l>
	<l>—Firft, Sir, you have debauch’d my Lovely Sifter,.</l>
	<l>The only one f had 5</l>
	<l>The hope and care of all our Noble Family 5</l>
	<l>Thou Prince didftravifh all her vertuefrom her.</l>
	<l>And left her nothing but a defperate fenfe of fhame.</l>
	<l>Which only ferv’d to do her felf that juftice,</l>
	<l>Which I had executed, had (he not prevented me.</l>
	<l>Fred . In this, upon my Soul, you do me wrong.</l>
	<l>Cnrt . Next, (oh how unlike a brave and generous Man ,)</l>
	<l>Without a caufe, you caft me from your bofom }</l>
	<l>Withdrew the Honour of your promis'd friendfiiip.</l>
	<l>And made me partner in my Sifters fate3</l>
	<l>Only with this difference, that (he</l>
	<l>You left to aft a Murtheron her felf 5</l>
	<l>And mine you would have been fo kind to’ve done</l>
	<l>With your own hand, but my refpeft prevented it.</l>
	<l>—Next, Sir, you ravifht Laura, from me.</l>
	<l>And under a pretence of facredfriendflffp,</l>
	<l>Youprov’d your (elf the worft of Enemies 3</l>
	<l>And that’s a crime you dare not fay was Ignorance,</l>
	<l>As you perhaps will plead, your fin to Cloris was. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Cloris > why what haft thou to do with Cloris-} </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> She was my Sifter, Frederick </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Thy Sifter. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, think of it well,</l>
	<l>A Lady of as pure and noble blood.</l>
	<l>As that of the great Duke thy .Father,</l>
	<l>Till you, bad man, infected it 3</l>
	<l>—Say fhould I Murtheryou for thisbafeaftion.</l>
	<l>Would you notcall it a true Sacrifice?</l>
	<l>And would not Heaven and Earth forgive it too ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> No, had I known that fhe had been thy Sifter,</l>
	<l>I had receiv’d her as a gift from Heaven,</l>
	<l>And Co I would do. ftil).</l>
	<l>( 77 )</l>
	<l>Curt She muftbe fent indeecJJrom Heaven,</l>
	<l>If you receive her now. J'> r :> frr .:  v </l>
	<l>Fred, Is Cloris dead > oh how I was to blame! jVeeps</l>
	<l>. —Here thou may’ft finifh now the life thou threatn’ft.</l>
	<l>Curt . Now Sir, you know my juftice and my power 5</l>
	<l>Yet fince my Prince can filed a tear for cloris </l>
	<l>I can forgive him,—here Sir,—fend me to Clovis?</l>
	<l>[Kneels and offers his Sword.</l>
	<l>That mercy poffibly will redeem the reft.</l>
	<l>Of all the wrongs you’ve done me 5  '</l>
	<l>And you (hall find nothing but forrow here.</l>
	<l>And a poor broken heart that did adore you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Rife Cnrtius , and divide my Dukedom with me 5</l>
	<l>Do anything that may preferve thy life,</l>
	<l>And gain my Pardon , alas thy Honour’s fafe.</l>
	<l>Since yet none knows that Chris was thy Sifter,</l>
	<l>Or if they do, I muft proclaim this trjuth 5</l>
	<l>She dy’d thy Princes Wife. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> This tydings would be welcomto my Sifter,</l>
	<l>And I the fitting’ft man to bear that news.</l>
	<l>offers to flab himfelf is held by Fred. Laur .and Clor. who</l>
	<l>come in with I fab. dreffed like Phillibert, and the reft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Stay Curlius , and take me with thee in the way. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Laura my deareft Laura l how came you hither ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Commanded by your Letter, have you forgot it? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Cnrtius , look here, is not this Cloris face ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> The fame 5 oh my fweet Sifter, is it thee ?</l>
	<l> £Curt . goes to in/brace her, fie goes back. r </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Do not be fhyemy foul, it is thy Brother. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, a brother who.defpis’d his life,</l>
	<l>When he believ’d your’s loft or fham’d 5</l>
	<l>But now the Prince will take a care of it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> May I believe my foul fo truly bleft ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Yes Cloris , and thus low I begthy pardon,.? Kneels.</l>
	<l>For all the fears that I have made thee fuffer. J</l>
	<l>Enter all the reff 0 firfl Ant. and Alb. without their Vi firs. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Rife, Sir, it is my duty and my glory. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> S ; ye have pardons too to beg of you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>( 7 ) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Antonio add Alberto , what turn'd Bravo's?</l>
	<l>I am amaz’d. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Y ou’l ceafe your wonder Sir, when you (hall know,</l>
	<l>-—Thofe Braves which formerly belong’d to you.</l>
	<l>Are now maintain’d by me 5 which Pietro hir’d</l>
	<l>For this nights fervice 3 and from them we learnt</l>
	<l>What was to be done, (though not onwhorn)</l>
	<l>But that vve gueft, and thought it but our duty</l>
	<l>To put this cheat on Curtius 3</l>
	<l>Which had we feen had been refolv’d to kill you 3</l>
	<l>H ad been by us prevented 5</l>
	<l>The Ladies too would needs be Curtezans</l>
	<l>Toferveyour Highness. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Fme much oblig’d to them, as you3</l>
	<l>—Cloris , a while I’le leave thee with thy Brother,</l>
	<l>Till I have reconcil’d thee to my Father 5</l>
	<l>To Marry me, is what he long has wifh’tfor,</l>
	<l>And will, l know, receive this news with joy. [ ‘Ex . Prince. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Here’s fine doings 5 what am I like to come to if he</l>
	<l>Turn honeft now ? this is the word piece of inconftancy i</l>
	<l>He ever was guilty of 3 to change ones humour, or fo, j</l>
	<l>Sometimes is nothing 3 but to change nature, </l>
	<l>To turn good on a ludden, and never give a man 1</l>
	<l>Civil warning, is a defeat not to be endur’d 3 '</l>
	<l>I’lefee the end oti’t though. [Goes out. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Here Antonio — imagine how I love thee.</l>
	<l>Who make thee fuch a Prefent.</l>
	<l>IG iveskim Clarina, who is dresf jujl as Ifmena rr>as 3 and</l>
	<l>Ifmena in Mafqning habit. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> C Ur in a , can you pardon my offence.</l>
	<l>And bless me with that Love,</l>
	<l>Ygu have but juftly taken from me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>cUr.</speaker>
	<l> You wrong me, Sir, I ne’re withdrew my heart}</l>
	<l>Though you, but too unkindly, did your confidence. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Do not upbraid me, that I was fo to blame,</l>
	<l>Isfhame enough 3 pray pardon, and forget it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> I do. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> Alberto 3 to (hew my gratitude in What Imay, ></l>
	<l>V Y‘ ' Si 7</l>
	<l>I</l>
	<l>[shows Ifm.</l>
	<l>( 79 )</l>
	<l>I beg you would receive ifmena from me </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Whofe this ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> Ifmena , whom I promis’d thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb .</speaker>
	<l> Itis clarina 3 do you mock my pain? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> By Heaven not I3 this is Clarina> Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> That thy wife Clarina !</l>
	<l>A beauty which till now I never faw. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> Sure thou art mad, didft thou not give her me but now ?</l>
	<l>And haft not entertain’d her all this night. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Her habit and her vizard did deceive me 5</l>
	<l>I took her for this Lady,—oh bleft miftake ! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> I fee you’re in the dark, but lie unfold the riddle 3</l>
	<l>—Sir, in the paft’agefrom the Monaftery,</l>
	<l>Attended only by my Confeftor,</l>
	<l>A Gentleman, a Paftenger, in the fame Boat,</l>
	<l>Addreft himfelf to me 3</l>
	<l>And made a many little Courtfhips to me:</l>
	<l>I being veil’d, he knew not who receiv’d them.</l>
	<l>Nor what confu lion they begot in me, </l>
	<l>At the firft light, 1 grew to great efteems of him.</l>
	<l>1</l>
	<l>But when I heard him fpeak—</l>
	<l>I’me not afham’d to fay he was my Conquerour 3 </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Oh Madam was it you ?</l>
	<l>Who by your converfation in that Voyage,</l>
	<l>Gave medifqniets.</l>
	<l>Which nothing but your eyes could reconcile again. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> ’TwasI whom you deceiv’d with fome fuch language 3</l>
	<l>—After my coming home, I grew more melancholy.</l>
	<l>And by my lilence did increafe my pain 3</l>
	<l>And foon Clarina. found 1 was a Lover,</l>
	<l>Which I confeftat laft, and nam’d the objeft 3</l>
	<l>She told me of your friendfthp with Antonio ,</l>
	<l>And gave me hopes that I again (hould fee you:</l>
	<l>—But Iftbella over-heard the Plot,</l>
	<l>Which, Sir, Antonio did contrive with you.</l>
	<l>To make a feigned Courtlhip to Clarina ,</l>
	<l>And told us all the ftory. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Oh how I’me ravilht with my happiness!. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l></l>
	<l>( 8 °) </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>ifm.</speaker>
	<l> Clarina 0 Sir, at fir ft was much inrag’d.</l>
	<l>And vow’d (he would revenge her on Antonio .5</l>
	<l>But I befought her to be pleas’d again.</l>
	<l>And faid T would contrive a Counter-Plot,</l>
	<l>Should fatisfie her htinour and revenge 5</l>
	<l>Thus, Sir I got a garment like to hers.</l>
	<l>And to be Courted, though but in jeft, by you, ></l>
	<l>I run all hazards of my Brothers anger, </l>
	<l>And your opinion of my lightness too.  </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clar.</speaker>
	<l> ’Twas a temptation. Sir, I would not venture on.</l>
	<l>Leaf!: from the reafonsof a juft revenge.</l>
	<l>And fo much beauty as Alberto own’d</l>
	<l>My vertue (hould not well fecure your intereft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> But why Tfmena was that killing Plot,</l>
	<l>When I was hid behind the Arras, for now Iconfess all. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> To make Alberto confident of my Love,</l>
	<l>And try his Friendfhipto the utmoftpoint,</l>
	<l>—Antonio too I found had fome referves,</l>
	<l>Which I believ’d his Amity to you.</l>
	<l>Alb, Yes, Madam, whilft I took you for his Wife,</l>
	<l>I thought it crime enough but to adore you 5</l>
	<l>But now I may with honour own my paffion 5</l>
	<l>I will, Ifmena> confidently allure you.</l>
	<l>That I will dye, unless you pity me. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifm.</speaker>
	<l> She that durft tell you. Sir, how much (he lov’d,</l>
	<l>When you believ’d it was a fin to do fo 5</l>
	<l>Will now makegood that promife with Antonio's leave. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant .</speaker>
	<l> With perfect joy, Ifmena,! refign thee.</l>
	<l>gives him fftnena. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> By double tyes you now unite our Souls: [To Ant.</l>
	<l>Though I can hardly credit what I fee.</l>
	<l>The happiness fo newly is arriv’d.</l>
	<l>Enter Prince, Lor. andGu\\. ivhocomes upferaping to Cloris. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> My Father is the kindeft man on earth.</l>
	<l>And Cloris (hall be welcomtohisbofom 5</l>
	<l>Who’lemakehim happy in my reformation:</l>
	<l>—Here Curtim , take Laura y who I find,</l>
	<l>Had rather be my Sifter then iny Mi ftress 5 1</l>
	<l>«o</l>
	<l>The Duke commands it fo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Curt.</speaker>
	<l> Til] you have pardon'd me my late offences</l>
	<l>I muft deny my felf fo great a happineft. QGurt. Kneels\ </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Rile,, you have it.</l>
	<l> Enter Salvator. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Salv.</speaker>
	<l> Is here not a Runagado belongs tome ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> No, Sir, my faith’s entire.</l>
	<l>And Curlius has the keeping of it.</l>
	<l>Salv . Who made him Mafterof it, hau > </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lau.</speaker>
	<l> Heaven, my Inclinations, and the Prince. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lalv.</speaker>
	<l> Three powerful oppofers 5</l>
	<l>Take her, fince it muft be fo 3</l>
	<l>And may ’ft thou be happy with her.</l>
	<l>Fred . Alberto , would this Court afforded</l>
	<l>A Lady worthy thee. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Alb.</speaker>
	<l> Sir, I’me already fped, I humbly thank you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Sped, quoth ye, Heaven defend</l>
	<l>Me from fuch fortune. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Lorenzo , I hd forgot thee 3 thou (halt e’ne marry too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Y ou may command me any thing but Marrying. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>jfib.</speaker>
	<l> What think y ou then of a fmooth-fac’d Boy } </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> A Pox on him, fure he will not tell now, will he? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Jfib.</speaker>
	<l> My Lord, I beg your leave to challenge Lorenzo. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> What to a Duel Phillibert ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor .</speaker>
	<l> Thill, rhill. hold, do not ruine the reputation</l>
	<l>Of a man that has aquir’d fame amongft the Femal fex 3</l>
	<l>I proteft 1 did but jeft. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> But, Sir, I’meinearneft with you. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> This is not Phillibert. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> No,Sir,but Isabella —that was Thillibert fjo inting to Clor. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l> Yes, Sir, I wasthe happy boy tobe belov’d.</l>
	<l>When Clork was forgotten. .» </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Oh how you raife my love and fhame 3</l>
	<l>But why did Isabella change her habit ? </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clo.</speaker>
	<l> Only to talie my place, leaft you (houldmiss me.</l>
	<l>Who being with Laura , at the lodgings of Clarina 3</l>
	<l>And comparing the words of her Letter,</l>
	<l>With what the Bravo’s had confeft to Antonio ,</l>
	<l>. M We</l>
	<l>We found the Plot which was laid for you,</l>
	<l>And joyn’d all to prevent it. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> ’Twas Pure the work of Heaven. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifdb.</speaker>
	<l> And now. Sir, I come to claim a husband here. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Name him, and take him. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ifab.</speaker>
	<l> Lorenzo Sir. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Of all cheats, commend me to a waiting-Gentlewomany</l>
	<l>I: her Husband! </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Ant.</speaker>
	<l> lama witness to that truth. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> ’Tis plain againft you, come you muft be honeft. , </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Will you compel me to’t againft my will > (</l>
	<l>Oh tyranny, confider I am a man of quality and fortune, i</l>
	<l>Ifab, As for my qualities, you know I have fufficient.</l>
	<l>And fortune, thanks to your bounty, confiderable too. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> No matter he has enough for both. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> Nay, Sir, an you be againft me,</l>
	<l>’Tis time to reform in my own defence 5</l>
	<l>But ’tis a thing T never confider’d, or thought on. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Marry firft, and confider afterwards. I </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Lor.</speaker>
	<l> That’sthe ufual way Icoqfess 1</l>
	<l>Come Isabella, fince the Prince commands it 5  j</l>
	<l>I do not love thee, but yet Tie not forfwear it 3</l>
	<l>Since a greater miracle then that is wrought .3</l>
	<l>And that’s my Marrying thee:</l>
	<l>Well, ’tis well thou art none of the moft beautiful,</l>
	<l>I (hould fwear the Prince had fome defigns on thee efte. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Clor.</speaker>
	<l>Y es Guilliamfince thou. haft been fo faithful, [Clot.Jpeas</l>
	<l>I dare alTure thee L//C74 (hall be thine. fafadeto Guil. </l>
</sp>
<sp>
	<speaker>Fred.</speaker>
	<l> Come my fair Cloris, and inveftthy felf</l>
	<l>In all the Glories, which I lately promis’d:</l>
	<l>—And Ladies, you’l attend her to the Court,</l>
	<l>And (hare the welcoms which the Duke provides her 5</l>
	<l>Where all the fallies of my flattering youth,</l>
	<l>Shall be no more remembr 5 d, but as paft 5</l>
	<l>Since ’tis a race that mull: by Man be run,</l>
	<l>I’me happy in my youth it was begun 5</l>
	<l>It ferves my future Manhood to improve,</l>
	<l>Wh ich (hall be facrific’d to War and Love.</l>
	<l>Curtain Falls.</l>
	<l>Epilogue fpoen by Cloris</l>
	<l>L Adies the Prince teas kjnd at lafl.</l>
	<l>But all the danger is notpass’dj</l>
	<l>1 cannot happy be till you approve,</l>
	<l>My hafiy condefention to his Love.</l>
	<l>'Twos want of Art’, notVertue was my Crime,</l>
	<l>And that's ,1 vow, the Authors faulty not mine :</l>
	<l>she might have made the Women pitiless ,</l>
	<l>But that had harder been tdi me than this :</l>
	<l>she might have made our Lovers conflant too,</l>
	<l>AworkwhichHeavenitfelf canfcarcely doj</l>
	<l>But (imple Nature never taught the way, </l>
	<l>To hide thojepajfions which ffje mufl obey. 5</l>
	<l>Humble Cottages and Cells,</l>
	<l>Where Innocence and Virtue dwells 5</l>
	<l>Then Courts no more fecure can be.</l>
	<l>From Love and dangerous flattery.</l>
	<l>Love in rural triumph reigns,</l>
	<l>As much a God amongfl the Swains,</l>
	<l>As if the Sacrifices paid,</l>
	<l>Were wounded hearts by Monarchs made j .</l>
	<l>And this might well excufe m offence.</l>
	<l>If it be Jo to Love a Prince.</l>
	<l>But Ladies, tis your hands alone.</l>
	<l>And not his power can raife me to a Throne j</l>
	<l>Without that aid I cannot reign ,</l>
	<l>But will return back, to my flocks again.</l>
	<l>Guilliam advances</l>
	<l>Guill. How go from Court! nay zay not zo.</l>
	<l>Hear me but Jpeaf before you go s</l>
	<l>Whoy zay the Leadies fldould refufe ye.</l>
	<l>The Bleads Tmefire would better ufiye</l>
	<l>So long as ye are kind and young,</l>
	<l>I kpow they l clap ye right or wrong.</l>
	<l>FINIS.</l>